<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entailment-corpus lang="EN">
  <pair id="1" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Climate change would affect absolutely everywhere on earth.</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="2" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     All that white fur will make them sitting ducks if the snow and ice melt away.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="3" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is usually accepted that climate change happens and affects oceans and Earth as an ecosystem.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="4" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This further may influence the economy in various countries and ultimately the lives of the people living there.</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="5" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Free speech is ALL speech.</t>
    <h>Climate Skeptics Should All Be Arrested</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="6" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
    <t>We had the medieval warm period, the roman warm period, the Minoan warm period and the Holocene maximum.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="7" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First my opponent says that I should have asked questions about the structure earlier in the debate but ignores the fact that, in the comment section, I did ask about the order of the debate and explain what I thought it meant.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="8" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent throws around a bunch of irrelevant facts to try to disprove highly credible and peer reviewed articles.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="9" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Rebuttals: Strong hurricane numbers have stayed almost constant since 1880: http://commdiginews.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="10" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent uses the tired strategy of cherry picking evidence and red herrings by climate change deniers.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="11" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My first source shows beyond a resonable doubt man-made climate change exists.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="12" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    R1 Acceptance R2-3 Arguments amp; rebuttals R4 No new arguments  You beat me last time, I figured its time to challenge you to a rematch.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="13" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I gladly accept your debate and look forward to your arguments.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="14" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Trump, who backed climate action in 2009 but now describes climate change as “$%^amp;”, is also out of step with the US and other governments’ efforts to turn emissions-cutting pledges into concrete actions in the wake of the Paris climate agreement.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump is a climate change denier.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="15" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     As a devout socialist (coughs and splutters- apparently the word communist is illegal nowadays) I can confirm that the idea of an environment is a plot to destroy the capitalist infidels of the west, the idea is to push their focus so far into ideas of global warming and the environment that they will not see the coming revolution.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="16" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would say the idea of the environment started with Charles Darwin in 1859.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="17" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm not sure where some people get these ideas from, but I think this is so crazy I can't even see the other point of view.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="18" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Co2 and global temperature have a two way causality relationship.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and is a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="19" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That the deniers are whistle blowers.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="20" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is an overwhelming scientific consensus climate change presents a serious risk to the future of the Earth and to mankind.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="21" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Assume for a second that the deniers are wrong.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="22" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would hate to see a 15 year old teenager go to jail for running off at the mouth.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="23" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We could also find out years from now that children aren't harmed in the production of child porn even though the evidence right now is substantial and overwhelming children are being harmed by child porn.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="24" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You want both sides to be able to debate-- but there is nothing really to debate.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="25" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My opponents second argument states, '''When the Earth comes out of an ice age, the warming is not initiated by CO2 but by changes in the Earth's orbit.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="26" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ''When the Earth comes out of an ice age, the warming is not initiated by CO2 but by changes in the Earth's orbit.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="27" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Manmade global climate change is the general increase in temperature at rapid rates that is mainly caused by CO2 from industry increases.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="28" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Especially when 25% of all Co2 produced by man has been released in the last 20 years and in that time there has been NO NET WARMING.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="29" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Fact 1: Co2 is a weak greenhouse gas.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="30" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent's argument seems endless and confusing.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="31" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Man Made Climate Change, The FACTS:  1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the world's climate: Many people I have met say, 'Manmade global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!' but how do you actually test that.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="32" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     According to your second argument, Co2 is at 400 ppm.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="33" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for being honest and admitting you don't understand my arguments.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="34" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'has reached 400 parts per million (ppm) for the first time in recorded history, according to data from the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii.' [3]Impact, there is a clear and strong positive correlation between CO2 and tempature.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="35" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm putting this under religion since people are talking faith based approaches to climate change.I have noticed that a surprising number of people still think global climate change is a hoax.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="36" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Maybe, just maybe if I had a year to respond I could defeat you.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="37" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Here are my reasons: 1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the world's climate: Many people I have met say, 'Man made global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!' but how do you actually test that.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="38" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is not doubt in my mind that Co2 causes warming.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="39" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My evidence that CO2 has a huge impact is here:  1: My opponent has acknowledged that CO2 is a green house gas.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="40" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My opponents 1st point states that there is no hard proof that CO2 from humans is the most important part to causing global warming.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="41" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponents first second and third points state, 'My opponent has acknowledged that CO2 is a green house gas.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="42" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I've shown multiple times that the predictions of those claiming manmade climate change is going to destroy the world have been incorrect.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="43" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent is correct the Earth's temperature has been hotter a long time ago.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="44" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Nature still produces FAR more CO2 than man.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="45" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is a much deeper topic and, i'll say again, this is a scientific debates.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="46" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, where I disagree is the threat.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="47" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In this round I will be refuting my opponent's arguments and I will be resupporting my own arguments My opponent stated'First my arguments still stand.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="48" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> However IPCC's definition of Global Climate Change requires such a correlation and if such a correlation is not apparent than Climate Change theory is flawed and thus Global Climate Change would not exist. </t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="49" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> However, my entire case has been in contradiction to the inconvenient truth documentary, I have offered scientific in direct contradiction to the scientific evidence in the movie.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="50" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Fossil Fuels do not cause an increase in CO2 emissions, which makes the first part of the IPCC's basic version of global warming invalid.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="51" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Argument one, burning of fossil fuels increase Co2.I've shown that the EPA states that burning of fossil fuels increase the greenhouse gas of CO2.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="52" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have noticed that a surprising number of people still think global climate change is a hoax.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="53" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Google docs are not a violation of conduct.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="54" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    72% of the totally emitted greenhouse gases is carbon dioxide (CO2), 18% Methane and 9% Nitrous oxide (NOx).</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="55" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No rational person could see the evidence and still deny it, unless the oppressive capitalists were warping that person's views to further their own agenda of ruthless self-interest.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="56" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your first source: loaded a 404 page.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="57" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent again has failed to prove his point, he claims that CO2 causes global warming, then shows that CO2 emmissions are increasing and so is the global temparture.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="58" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Like I said before, you have only provenb that there is more CO2 iun the environment, not that it is heating up.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="59" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Every single one of your sources only proves that the environment has morecarbon dioxide, not that this is increasing the tempature, infact the icacaps are growing.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a fraud</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="60" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now, I believe that Co2 has a small effect on the climate, but there is simply no evidence saying that we will die.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="61" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As you can see, my opponent has stated the exact opposite of what is true in regards to climate change.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="62" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And while I don't personally believe that man made climate change is as big as you stated, but we do have an $8,000,000,000 department called the Environmental Protection Agency.' Climate change is real and is a threat.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="63" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    With the environment becoming increasingly an issue I think its a high time we elect a green party representative.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="64" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    While I normally don't find it important to bring up, but people often bring it up, but Johnson's achievements as a Republican are not meaningless just because he is now a Libertarian, for as a republican, Johnson upheld a strictly Libertarian sort of Raegan Coolidge like platform, so nothing really changed except party.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="65" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now your claim that Jill Stein has a more prestigious degree is true in fact, but agin, its not a political degree, meanwhile Gary Johnson has a degree in political science.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="66" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My only rules are that you pick one of these four candidates and that you are respectful and civil throughout the debate.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="67" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Jill Stein.</t>
    <h>Gary Johnson is our best choice for president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="68" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    But keep in mind he's the head of a Church, not a Climate Committee.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="69" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have immense respect for Pope Francis.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="70" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks for accepting.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="71" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has dropped every issues except the ozone layer.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="72" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I chose to play defense and only address the points you made, which were few.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="73" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have noticed that a surprising number of people still think global climate change is a hoax.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="74" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You simply said that Co2 levels are higher then we expected.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="75" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Now on to your claim of Co2 levels.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="76" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Back in the 70s virtually every scientist agreed that we were going into a massive ice age, and now they have flip flopped and now think the globe is warming.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="77" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In most cases, you will see that studies that indicate a rapid change are botched, as seen in my 97% debate.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="78" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    R2 rebuttals'I would like to thank my opponent for the opportunity to be able to debate this fascinating topic.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="79" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My opponent unfortunately makes some shallow assumptions, in that they believe Donald Trump legitimately believes everything he's said.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="80" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In other words you claim Donald Trump is a compulsive liar who will say anything to turn heads.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="81" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Anyway, my contentions haven't been addressed at all.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="82" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     In your own link there is further proof that Donald Trump is not a believer in climate change and thus thinks its a hoax.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="83" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Claim: Donald claims climate change is a hoax.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="84" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ok so my opponent conceded the first 2 rounds of the debate and decided to bring a completely new contention the very last round.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump thinks climate change is a hoax.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="85" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If pandas refuse to mate quickly enough to populate the planet then screw them, let them die out.</t>
    <h>This world should be polluted</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="86" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     82% of the population uses fossil fuels, that's more than half the world.</t>
    <h>This world should be polluted</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="87" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Actually people use 1.2 billion vehicles in the world + 36.5 million smokers smoke each day thats 1277.5 million a year.</t>
    <h>This world should be polluted</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="88" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Even with all of the smokers and drivers, add in all of the factories and air travel, add in coal use and everything else we do...people still only produce 3% of greenhouse gas.</t>
    <h>This world should be polluted</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="89" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The debate challenge asks whether PolitiFact has a liberal bias.</t>
    <h>Does the website "PolitiFact" have a liberal bias?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="90" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    PolitiFact's leftward lean does not yet receive the full attention it deserves, so I appreciate the opportunity to make the case.</t>
    <h>Does the website "PolitiFact" have a liberal bias?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="91" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     'The 2012 study showed the apparently subjective 'Pants on Fire' rating was 74 percent more likely to fall on a Republican false statement than a Democrat false statement, covering the years from 2007 through 2011.</t>
    <h>Does the website "PolitiFact" have a liberal bias?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="92" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    They rate more claims by conservatives false then they do liberals.</t>
    <h>Does the website "PolitiFact" have a liberal bias?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="93" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Environmental law has developed in response to emerging awareness and concern over issues impacting the globe.</t>
    <h>environmental education and not environmental prosecution is the answer to waste management problems</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="94" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    environmental education does not advocate a particular newpoint of course of action but rather teaches individuals how to weigh various sides of an issue through critical thinking and it enhances their own problem solving and decision making skills.</t>
    <h>environmental education and not environmental prosecution is the answer to waste management problems</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="95" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has forfeited the debate.</t>
    <h>environmental education and not environmental prosecution is the answer to waste management problems</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="96" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Please extend my arguments.</t>
    <h>environmental education and not environmental prosecution is the answer to waste management problems</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="97" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>'I will build a great, great wall on our southern border,And I will make Mexico pay for that wall. </t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="98" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Trump's few sayings 'My parents came all the way from Germany to America not to see it overtaken by immigrants.' 'Crooked Hilary Clinton' 'extremely credible source has called my office and told me that Barack Obama's birth certificate is a fraud' 'Ariana Huffington is unattractive, both inside and out.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="99" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hello there Mr.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="100" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Those are just some bars for a good ending: I drop my lines like bombs down the trenches of Iwo JimaLife curls up on its back as the grim reaper stands supremerThe mushroom-could expands but it ain't what it seemsThat's the penis of Rahul Gandhi up the skies of Hiroshima.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="101" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    How many hours did you spend preparing all that rap.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="102" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Trump seems to be more serious, it would be fun to see what he does as president.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump (pro) vs Rahul Gandhi (con)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="103" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con also states, 'It may promote development of underwater cities as they would have to do it for survival.' I thought we were going to try and solve global warming, not run away from it.3) We must find a viable replacement of fossil fuels rather than targeting the removal of co2.</t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="104" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, currently global warming isn't killing anyone as such, yes the Polar bears are losing some habitat, but according to my sources Arctic ice had increased from 2010, which is contrary to the expectations of global warming experts.</t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="105" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Not hydropower, not solar panels, but fossil fuels.</t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="106" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> We shouldn't be focused on 'JUST planting trees.' </t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="107" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    '1) Currently, it would take more time for global warming to become extremely lethal than it would be for the fuel crisis.</t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="108" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Currently, it would take more time for global warming to become extremely lethal than it would be for the fuel crisis.</t>
    <h>global warming (pro) vs fuel crisis (con) which is more important?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="109" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank beforeifall for accepting this debate.CO2's Effect on TemperatureFirst, correlation.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="110" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Numerous alternate causes to global warming prove that humans are not the primary source.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="111" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All arguments must be visible inside this debate, and character limits must not be broken.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="112" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Consider this my acceptance.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="113" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> In other words, whenever the northern hemisphere is warming, the southern hemisphere is cooling, and vice versa.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="114" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hopefully my opponent will at least respond to my original arguments.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="115" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Your first point was how even though data shows a correlation between CO2 emissions and temperature, carbon emission is not the largest factor.</t>
    <h>CO2 emissions are directly responsible for climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="116" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Macquarie Dictionary defines the term 'climate change' as- a significant change in the usual climatic conditions especially that thought to be caused by global warming.</t>
    <h>CO2 emissions are directly responsible for climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="117" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Before I begin I would like to initially reinforce the topic of the debate: CO2 emissions are DIRECTLY responsible for climate change.</t>
    <h>CO2 emissions are directly responsible for climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="118" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I do know that the topic is 'CO2 is the largest factor in global warming', and that is what I am arguing.</t>
    <h>CO2 emissions are directly responsible for climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="119" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I do know that the topic is 'CO2 is the largest factor in global warming', and that is what I am arguing.</t>
    <h>CO2 emissions are directly responsible for climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="120" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I obviously recognize that many of these side zoos/aquariums practice animal cruelty, which is definetley illegal.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="121" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Zoos are are valuable for public education, awareness, and scientific research.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="122" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I admit the zoos aren't the ideal situation for animals.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="123" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    One of the researchers for the British study said: 'In many cases, a trip to the zoo had a negative impact on the children's understanding of animals and habitats.' Showing children animals in zoos simply teaches them that animals are ours to control.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="124" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As the spend a few seconds at each exhibit and often taunt the animals for entertainment.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="125" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Zoos claim to be good for many things, but they do more harm than good overall.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="126" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This debate is about whether we should be keeping animals in zoos and aquariums.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="127" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Should animals be kept in zoos/aquariums?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="128" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Tucan sam yall.</t>
    <h>Daylight Savings Time Causes Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="129" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It's only obvious that an extra hour of sunlight will warm the planet and melt the Polar Ice Caps.</t>
    <h>Daylight Savings Time Causes Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="130" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    When the ice melts, the oceans rise, and coastal cities flood, don't blame it on me.</t>
    <h>Daylight Savings Time Causes Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="131" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     First, 2050 is a projection given by Bill Gates for zero emissions throughout the whole world IF serious and drastic changes are made in reducing of C02 levels.</t>
    <h>Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="132" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Also, educating more people puts more minds to work on solutions to the issues at hand.</t>
    <h>Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="133" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> I will be arguing against the statement that 'Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global climate change.' </t>
    <h>Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="134" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     All you have to do is tell me what that is and I will go and get it.</t>
    <h>Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="135" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change.</t>
    <h>Global Poverty, Education, and hunger are greater issues than global warming/ climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="136" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Sorry for my long delay, I have been busy  Argument: While it is true that currently the climb of global warming is slow, just wait for the 'point of no return.' Haven't heard of it.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="137" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In about two and a half centuries, our global temperature has only gone up by that non-remarkable amount (0.00612 per year).</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="138" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First things first (I'm the realest..gosh that song's old), if we were to ensure the cooperation of our world organization, then we could accomplish so much more.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="139" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Many websites say that if global warming was stopped, it would help world peace a lot.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="140" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="141" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    World peace is an issue of the utmost urgency.</t>
    <h>Global warming is a bigger issue than World Peace</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="142" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Before I lay out my arguments I would like to make one clarification: the pro side is not arguing that prevention is the ultimate solution.</t>
    <h>Nations should work to prepare for climate change instead of preventing it.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="143" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The present effects of global warming and other forms of climate change are well documented.</t>
    <h>Nations should work to prepare for climate change instead of preventing it.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="144" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I spent some time on this.</t>
    <h>Nations should work to prepare for climate change instead of preventing it.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="145" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Well this was kind of fun.</t>
    <h>Nations should work to prepare for climate change instead of preventing it.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="147" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro has ventured away from his original resolution that technology is making humans graceless by bringing up issues like global warming and climate change.</t>
    <h>Has tech wizard made our life graceless</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="148" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As said by my con ,'Technology has advanced the human race as whole'.</t>
    <h>Has tech wizard made our life graceless</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="149" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes the techs have made us cattle who are following the same path of getting a 'like' .From evolution we got tech and now our condition is deteriorating.</t>
    <h>Has tech wizard made our life graceless</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="150" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro has forfeited.They failed to uphold their resolution and my points remain essentially unrefuted.Thanks to Pro for an interesting debate, I had fun.Vote Con.</t>
    <h>Has tech wizard made our life graceless</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="151" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I think green spaces are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="152" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     As for my opponent's global warming claim, she did not provide any evidence for its existence, so her claim should be rejected as the baseless claim that it is.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="153" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Green spaces are the primary need of the people because they are the only one on whom our whole life depends.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="154" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Having said that, since she has yet to offer any argument of her own, I am still without anything to rebut.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="155" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank my opponent for creating this debate.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="156" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And wherever you will look , you will find the same thing.</t>
    <h>Open green areas are more important than expansion of cities for economic progress.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="157" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> A carbon tax is a tax levied on the carbon content of fuels, which results in most carbon emissions -- emissions of carbon dioxide, which increases temperature, and occasionally carbon monoxide, which is toxic.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="158" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm disappointed that my opponent forfeited.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="159" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The debate will use the 'opt-in' voting standards outlined here.First round acceptance only.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="160" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I hope everything is fine with my opponent, seeing as they have forfeited.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="161" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ok let's see how this goes (fake swagger) lets see if I can somehow pull this off.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="162" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Dude I forfeited, it happens sorry, anyways I concede the debate.</t>
    <h>The US should adopt a carbon tax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="163" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The word 'main' as used in the debate heading presents the position that humanity's contribution to global warming is greater in magnitude than any other factor.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="164" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Its true , there have been cold periods every year.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="165" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>The IPCC Report of 2015 states: Its extremely likely that more than half of the observed increase in global average surface temperature from 1951 to 2010 wascaused by the anthropogenic increase in GHG concentrations and other anthropogenic forcings together.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="166" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will restate, than in order to establish that the primary cause of global warming is human activity, it is necessary to quantify the amount and effect (not qualify).</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="167" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And it is also not my possible (to my knowledge) to quantify the impact of natural causes on climate change as it is unpredictable and can change any time.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="168" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes, I agree with Pro's sources in Round 5 that list all of the ways in which human activity plays a role in affecting global climate.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="169" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Geographers and Geologists consider the state of the Earth at time present to be in an ice age, albeit a late stage.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="170" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept and look forward to the debate.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="171" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First round is acceptance only.</t>
    <h>Humanity is the main cause of global warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="172" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Framework:Economic Globalization: “The trans-national increase in trade and capital transfers across national boundaries.” [http://tinyurl.com...] If I can prove economic globalization will have a net negative effect, I win.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="173" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now if we do not accept economic globalization, it will only isolate our nation and limit out options.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="174" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> No new arguments in the final roundThe BoP is sharedFailure to comply to these stipulations or following round structure renders an automatic loss.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="175" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this debate, and may the best man win.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="176" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Isolation if we don't accept globalizationThis point is objectively false for a number of reasons:1.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="177" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would post my argument but sense I forfeited the last round and the rules say no forfeiting I will admin that con wins.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="178" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend arguments.</t>
    <h>Economic Globalization</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="179" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Yes, recent measurements of the ice caps do indicate an increase.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="180" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Cold water sinks from the arctic regions and circulates toward the equator where it rises and warms to return back to where it came pushed by winds and currents.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="181" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Also there is no scientific evidence that the reason 'global warming' is happening because of man.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="182" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No rebuttal provided.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="183" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No rebuttal offered.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="184" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No rebuttal.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Myth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="185" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    97 percent of climate scientists have confirmed that climate change is happening and that human activity is responsible.</t>
    <h>The claim that "97% of scientists agree 'man made global warming' exists" is a lie.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="186" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You claim that the 97% of scientists absolutely do not side with the notion that global warming is man-made.</t>
    <h>The claim that "97% of scientists agree 'man made global warming' exists" is a lie.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="188" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    -Further, I wanted to include some peer-review against cook's paper.Climate Consensus and 'Misinformation': A Rejoinder to Agnotology, Scientific Consensus, and the Teaching and Learning of Climate Change (PDF) [Archive](Science amp; Education, pp.</t>
    <h>The claim that "97% of scientists agree 'man made global warming' exists" is a lie.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="189" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The point to be addressed is that the FAO report, while the full report is seemingly not accessible, parts of it are, includes many sources of data potentially unrelated to to factory farming, such as deforestation and cropping.</t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="190" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, the majority of agricultural problems arising are not simply from 'factory farming'.</t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="191" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Efforts to halt global deforestation emissions must tackle this sector. ' </t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="192" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be representing the Con side, meaning that I will be debating that Factory Farming is not the number 1 cause of man made climate change.</t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="193" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     'Free range  This term is often found on meats, eggs, and dairy products, but the USDA only regulates use of the term as applied to poultry like chickens and turkeys.</t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="194" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I pro will argue that factory farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change.</t>
    <h>Factory Farming is the #1 cause of man-made global climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="195" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Look at figure 5 in source 1.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="196" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Neither the question nor I ever said humans were 'THE cause' of climate change, but they are far and away the most destructive and sudden cause.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="197" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Climate: the average course or condition of the weather at a place usually over a period of years as exhibited by temperature, wind velocity, and precipitationHumans do indeed play a role in climate change, but they do not explicitly 'cause' climate change.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="198" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    While your arguments are certainly convincing, they still in no way prove that humans are the direct cause of climate change.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="199" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And the entire earth is not warming.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="200" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Though natural amounts of carbon in the atmosphere vary from 180 to 300ppm, today the level is at 400ppm - higher than in the past 800,000 years.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change Caused by Humans?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="201" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is a debate about whether or not global warming is real.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="202" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would define 'real' as what the people think that say 'global warming' is 'real' think.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="203" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent says, 'Some of the new science on this tells us that instead of a 4.8 degree temperature increase by 2100 as a worst case scenario, the worst case is 1.8 degrees by 2100, which means it's within our ability to deal with it without doing anything much.' Please note that I am not arguing about whether global warming will rapidly increase in the future.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="204" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent says that global warming is real, but 'a lot slower than the models predicted'.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="205" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is absolutely no way to know what effect, if any, global temperature increase has on any particular weather event or weather trend.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="206" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would define 'real' as what the people think that say 'global warming' is 'real' think.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="207" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has even admitted that 'the world is warming up', and has called me 'slippery'.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="208" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That's real.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="209" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Some of the new science on this tells us that instead of a 4.8 degree temperature increase by 2100 as a worst case scenario, the worst case is 1.8 degrees by 2100, which means it's within our ability to deal with it without doing anything much.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="210" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Here's a definition of something real:  --- fire'crack'er G2;fī(ə)rG6;krakər/ noun a loud, explosive firework, typically wrapped in paper and lit with a fuse.</t>
    <h>Global warming is real</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="211" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'll start eating some bacon now  what  oh yeah the arguments 1) It’s really hot outside.2) What’s the big deal if global temperatures go up a few degrees.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="212" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Bacon God Pork is the most widely eaten meat in the world accounting for over 36% of the world meat intake.http://tinyurl.com...The Bacon God is not unhappy.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="213" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Because the Bacon God says so.)     Don't believe me.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="214" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming shouldn't be legalized.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="215" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that global warming doesn't exist, and Pro will be arguing that it does.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="216" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="217" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Round 4 of 5It is important to check your grammar and spelling, otherwise you may be penalized by the voters. And if I can take over this website, I can take over any website.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="218" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Wait.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="219" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    arGumentz: Gobal warming iz false becuz I dont liek da booty b0ss.</t>
    <h>Who can create the worst argument: Global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="221" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Global Warming: The state of which the Earth's temperature progressively and abnormally rises, which is attributed to the Greenhouse Effect that is caused by increased levels of carbon dioxide, other greenhouse gases, and pollutants in general.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="222" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Contradictory Glacial, Sea Level, and Temperature DataFigure 12 is interesting not because it counters any of my argument, but because it puts my opponents temperature, and sea level data in contradiction with it.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="223" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Atmospheric CO2 for 650,000 years. Doubt It's telling that my opponent makes the claim that it is irrefutable, and then uses Figure 2.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="224" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks to my opponent, it's been fun.I will respond to the points my opponent has made in this round, and clarify my case.But first of all, I am sure that I hadn't ignored a piece of my opponent's case.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="226" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  The correlation between increase in Carbon Dioxide and global temperature. Throughout the last 650,000 years, there have been seven cycles of glacial advances and retreats, where the carbon dioxide levels abruptly increased, then gradually decreased afterward.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="227" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks to my opponent.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="228" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks to my opponent for such a great debate!Counter-rebuttals==Counter 1: Contradiction?==My opponent asserts that my glacial, sea level and temperature figures are contradictory.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="229" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If you wish to debate any statistic, or figure you might want to consider reading the book in full.As women get older they toe out more as they walk.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="230" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Human Activity Is a Significant Factor in Global Warming on Planet Earth.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="231" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We may observe that humans release approximately 35 gigatons of CO2 a year.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="232" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All scientists agree that CO2 has some direct effect, increasing temperature by 1.1 degrees Celsius per doubling of CO2 concentration in the atmosphere.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="233" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con writes, 'My opponent has also dropped my opening graph in C1 r2 That also showed that CO2 levels are at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="234" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    PrefaceThis is the Final debate of the Official May Regular Tournament on solely highly controversial topics, hosted by Unitomic.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="235" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this challenge.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="236" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="237" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I hope my opponent is completely alright and happy, and is doing well.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="238" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Thank you and please vote Pro.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="239" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Forfeiture.</t>
    <h>Official May Tournament Final: Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="240" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Evaporation data is small enough to analyse in excel, but precipitation data would require a database or custom tools to work with.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="241" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 yearsResolution:Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years.DefinitionsGlobal Warming - A process of climate change frequently associated with the warming of the environment due to man made pollution.115 Years - For statistical limitations to be 1900 to 2014 and early 2015Accelerating the water cycle - A sustained increase in water evaporation, or precipitation beyond the first 30 years of the 115 year range, or 1900 to 1930.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="242" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Unfortunately my opponent has decided to go with only a contradiction, and not actually an argument.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="243" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It looks like my opponent isn't even active anymore.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="244" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Logicgt;Evidence  Evidence----gt;Failure  Failure----gt;You lose  I win.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="245" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That's not true.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="246" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes it has, Penguin.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="247" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  115 Years - For statistical limitations to be 1900 to 2014 and early 2015 Accelerating the water cycle - A sustained increase in water evaporation, or precipitation beyond the first 30 years of the 115 year range, or 1900 to 1930.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="248" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is bad.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="249" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Evaporation data is small enough to analyse in excel, but precipitation data would require a database or custom tools to work with.Analysis Method:In order to estimate precipitation, and evaporation levels I will be utilizing the NOAA GHCND weather station dataset.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="250" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent appears to be under the mistaken impression that I've plagiarized my argument, and my chart data.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="251" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And least that way it would be more fun when I destroy you.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="252" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My opponent makes the claim that global warming is bad, and should be stopped.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="253" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I still think that global worming is bad, and should be stopped.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="254" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That wouldn’t actually contradict my data since from 1990 there was in an increasing trend in precipitation due to a reduction in SO2 pollution.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="255" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Analysis Method:In order to estimate precipitation, and evaporation levels I will be utilizing the NOAA GHCND weather station dataset.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="256" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank medv4380 for presenting his arguments.The Water CycleI want to start by providing a brief description of the water cycle, and what it means to accelerate the water cycle.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  
  <pair id="258" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> If I'm reading my opponent's argument correctly, he seems to be arguing that solar activity is the cause of the evaporation increase, saying that the reduction in solar activity causes the Earth's magnetic field to weaken, causing more radiation to reach Earth.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="259" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'On average, land-use change has increased global runoff by 0.08 mm/year^2 and accounts for ~50% of the reconstructed global runoff trend over the last century.' There's still the other half that needs to be accounted for.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="260" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con will decide if R2 will have an Argument or Rebuttal in R1.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="261" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for challenging me to this debate.</t>
    <h>Global Warming has not accelerated the Water Cycle in the last 115 years</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="262" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ==Nuclear energy==My second point involves Nuclear energy, which was created because of the weapons like the A-Bomb.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="263" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      C1: Nuclear Weapons seriously threaten the human race   Nuclear weapons are so far one of the only weapons mankind has developed that could end the human race as we know it, and in fact, almost did more than once.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="264" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      Pro depends not on the main focus of this debate, that is, nuclear weapons, but rather nuclear power/energy.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="265" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Resolved: Nuclear weapons have helped our society.-First round: Acceptence-Second round: Affirmitive Construction-Third round: Rebuttal-Fourth round: Closing Arguments.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="266" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Forfeit - Points continue.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="267" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept the debate.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Nuclear Weapons have Helped our Society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="268" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now little about myself I'm a moderate Republican/independent living in a medium-size town of Joplin Missouri I'm here to change America to the right direction that we need or else we will never seen it again let's make America stronger.</t>
    <h>Presidential debate 2015</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="269" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  This will be a presidential debate format over a variety of issues</t>
    <h>Presidential debate 2015</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="270" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has accepted this presidential debate but he decided to forfeit it.</t>
    <h>Presidential debate 2015</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="271" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rand paul.</t>
    <h>Presidential debate 2015</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="272" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As debate over the Trans-Pacific Partnership heats up, questions about the benefits and drawbacks of free trade are being raised by people from all sides of the political spectrum.This debate will not be a defense of the TPP, as I do not know the full details of the bill.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="273" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="274" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The trade regulations I advocate are targeted towards specific problems with unfettered free trade.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="275" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'll start with my arguments and then do a rebuttal.Free trade poses an existential threat to human survival97% of climate scientists agree that humans are causing global warming.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="276" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      Free Trade is Beneficial to the Environment  'Free trade is incompatible with reducing emissions, slowing climate warming, and saving our planet.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="277" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Free Trade Increases Innovation and Efficiency The first reason one should support free trade is because open trade with other countries leads to maximized innovation and efficiency in the economy.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="278" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote Con.</t>
    <h>Free Trade Benefits the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="279" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Giving the monei to bethesda to develop fallout 4 more developlly will be better use of charity money.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="280" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    He states that because of help from other countries, 'by 2035, there will be almost no poor countries left in the world.' [1.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="281" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    (Look bro aint nothing wrong with dressin up like a pony and gettin f*cked all haters are just jelous they not gettin f*cked)  Im sick and tired of people giving their 'Money' to charities that 'Help' ' children' and try to fund 'cancer' research.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="282" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The BoP is on Pro to show that money normally going to charity should go to a video game.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="283" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote Con.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="284" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend.</t>
    <h>We should stop giving money to charity and give it to bethesda for more fallout 4 content</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="285" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This small linear increase of forcing, by itself, would have caused a modest global warming through the Cenozoic Era.' The CO2 levels caused a much higher forcing.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="286" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The 0.7 factor comes from the fact that the Earth reflects about 30% of the solar radiation it receives, and the 1/4 factor comes from spherical geometry.Changes in temperature are proportional to the energy imbalance.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="287" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Each year through our generation of electricity through coal, our consumption of petrol and oil and exhaust of our transportation, our destruction of natural filters such as plant life, phytoplankton and bodies of water have made our world a slightly different place that will radically change in the near future.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="288" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All arguments must be visible inside this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="289" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    To be honest, I thought it would be a fun thing to debate someone on something controversial and funny.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="290" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="291" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Well, then, I thank my opponent for presenting the arguments he did.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="292" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="293" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The debate right now is about climate change, which since it has been undefined, I define as 'a long-term change in the earth's climate, especially a change due to an increase in the average atmospheric temperature:' (dictionary.com).</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="294" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Everyone agrees that CO2 has some direct effect, at least 1 degree C per doubling of CO2 concentration.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="295" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Paleoclimatology does have an application in this debate: whether or not CO2 causes (or doesn’t cause) past climate changes is important.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="296" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     To clarify 'on balance', I am not arguing that climate change is entirely man made.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="297" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     - I refuted paleoclimate, showing that past records actually support AGW and that he misrepresented his sources gt; showed today was abnormally warm for this recent interglacial cycle gt; king's graph shows correlation  - his whole argument is a semantical ploy on origin and climate change.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="298" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This debate is not whether modern climate change is due to humans.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="299" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am negating this.Note: this is not semantics,as these are the common understandings of the topic.To claim that changes in the climate from over 4000 years ago is caused by humans is quite ridiculous.Climate change has been happening for millions of years.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="300" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'I actually support ...the Spanish inquisition, the murder of natives and so much more.' airmax1227  Acceptance.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Climate change is, on balance, anthropogenic in origin</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="301" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am very excited to have this debate, and I hope it goes well.This debate assumes that climate change has happened over the past centuries, and that over that period of time there has been a overall increase in global temperatures.</t>
    <h>Is Anthropogenic Global Warming Real?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="302" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is my first debate and I would like to make it a good one, so I am starting with global warming.</t>
    <h>Is Anthropogenic Global Warming Real?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="303" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will take the position that anthropogenic global warming is real and is caused by human activities.</t>
    <h>Is Anthropogenic Global Warming Real?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="304" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have nothing to refute, so please send some votes my way.</t>
    <h>Is Anthropogenic Global Warming Real?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="305" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      C1) Climate Sensitivity amp; Feedbacks  My first contention is to demonstrate CO2 has effects in rising the mean land-sea temperature.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="306" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank Kylar for this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="307" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I gladly accept this debate with my friend and I look forward to a great debate :).</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="308" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  How did global warming discussions end up hinging on what's happening with polar bears, unverifiable predictions of what will happen in a hundred years, and whether people are 'climate deniers' or 'global warming cultists?</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="309" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>       R2) Scientific Consensus  A study published in Science reviewed the ISI web of science in order to take a survey of relevant climate literature as to what the causes of climate change are.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="310" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    • Deserts get drier leaving to increased desertification.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="311" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rebuttal  My opponent has presented arguments completely irrelevant to the resolution, merely presenting *disadvantages* of global warming as opposed to actually creating a case that global warming is NOT caused by mankind.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="312" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank you for this debate, however I have had a rough go of it.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="313" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now, there is a good deal of evidence that humans are not causing global warming at all.</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="314" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I do believe that global warming exists, and I must correct you: my argument was not that global warming will have no repercussions on the environment at all.</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="315" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    What melting-ice-caps activists fail to realize is that most of Antarctica's ice is already underwater.</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="316" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    finale round exciting so as your explaining very well detailed in your counter arguments your are basically saying that there is no issue in global warming WHAT SO EVER and i guess it is how you see it really</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="317" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Even so global warming is still a big issue yes the earth has hot and cold periods but they may get worse and worse each time until eventually a whole species or country is wiped out by habitat loss or water levels rising</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="318" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    i think that global warming is an issue that we as people should act upon global warming has increased by a large amount and us being a main cause of it should find a way to figure a way to decrease the amount.</t>
    <h>is global warming an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="319" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Yes I agree that the Earths temperature is rising, that is no secret.I just do not belive that global warming is the reason why.My six propositions of alternate climate change are.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="320" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    What does the sun have to do with CO2 and global warming.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="321" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Is global warming real.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="322" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> -global warming is a misconception  -Polar icecaps melting are a result of the first theory i am going to bring up (next round).</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="323" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You first made the point about how I implied carbon dioxide is placed in the atmosphere by humans.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="324" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    that 1 kilogram of meat is responsible for the amount of carbon in the atmosphere as a car driving 250 kilometers.'</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="325" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You said yourself, 'that the co2 being placed in the atmosphere is causing natural changes'.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="326" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend all arguments.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="327" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Climate change belongs to the natural circle, global warming doesn't.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="328" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A significant tip of the hat to Con for their respect and generosity.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="329" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First of all, I'd like to thank Pro for accepting the debate and tip my hat to a clinical first round.I do concede one aspect of religion that is almost unambiguously positive: it provides individuals with a support group.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="330" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'll start by thanking Pro for an intelligent and thought-provoking debate.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="331" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I could have started by citing some very strong statistics that link religiosity with murder rates all over the World.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="332" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Once again, my apologies for my prior forfeit.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="333" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I freely admit that my sources for Round 1 are less than ideal.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="334" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Have lower rates of suicide [1]2.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="335" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    it's not that I haven't a lot to say, but it will probably benefit the gentle readers (and me) that I am forced to be concise in my final round.</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="336" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro will accept the burden of proof to show that religion makes the World a better place.I'm assuming that we're going to hear about charitable donations, better moral compasses and so on and so forth.I'll be ready :-).</t>
    <h>Religion makes the World a better place</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="337" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    - Beside the utter lack of sources amp; support for his arguments, Pro has yet to argue for the eradication of poverty, as affirmed in his resolution.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="338" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rebuttals:the fact we have reduced it puts us in a better position to be able to eradicate the remaining poverty.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="339" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I made the specific point that the fact we have reduced it puts us in a better position to be able to eradicate the remaining poverty.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="340" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     We know that we can significantly reduce poverty because there are countries that have done it like Norway and Denmark.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="341" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I believe we can {and afford} to ensure the income of every adult is over the poverty line {be it through welfare payments or something else}.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="342" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    - Thanks Pro for instigating the debate, amp; I accept his challenge.</t>
    <h>Poverty can and should be eradicated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="343" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I give you the above graph measuring the past 600 million years of CO2 levels are we are actually at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="344" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Clearly, the levels that CO2 is reaching are unsustainable.[1]The reason the CO2 rise is considered high is because the CO2 level is the highest in around 50 million years.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="345" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank lannan13 for accepting this debate.Human-Emitted Greenhouse GasesIt is known that CO2 levels are increasing.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="346" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We've decided to redo this debate since Lannan was unable to finish it earlier.Full ResolutionI will be arguing that mankind is the main cause of global warming.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="347" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="348" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    16k, you, and I have now all changed to the pro-AGW side.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="349" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has convinced me to his position, henceforth I can no longer argue my side.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="350" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pass.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="351" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Format R1: Acceptance R2: Constructive Case R3: Rebuttals R4: Rebuttals and Conclusion  *Edit* This debate was going to be for the beginners tourney, but we have changed topic.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="352" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    He should seek alternative data that supports his contention that, even if one assumes the data is reliable, I have unequivocally refuted.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="353" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I give you the above graph measuring the past 600 million years of CO2 levels are we are actually at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="354" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  We can see here that these percentages are indeed quite low and this was dropped by my opponent so I extend them across the board.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="355" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Humans are the source of the vast majority of resultant carbon dioxideThis figure shows the estimated balance of carbon dioxide emissions.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="356" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As I've previously mentioned: 'Because of this, atmospheric carbon dioxide is at the highest levels in approximately 15 to 20 million years[1].</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="357" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept and I would like to point out before the debate starts that in order for my opponent to win he must prove that Global Warming is Largely man-made, meaning that more than 50% is to be caused by humans.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="358" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Give my opponent all 7 points.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Largely Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="359" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  The world is changing all the time. Some people think it changes for the better ,while otherr think it worsens.In my opinion , the world around us is becoming better and better.</t>
    <h>Is the world changing for the better (pro for better con for not)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="360" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No, the world is not changing for the better.</t>
    <h>Is the world changing for the better (pro for better con for not)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="361" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Religion is becoming more of a solace for peooleSome conflicts are being resolved (US vs Cuba)But there are worse things in the world too:Rise of terrorists like Boko Haram and ISIS.</t>
    <h>Is the world changing for the better (pro for better con for not)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="362" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept, thank you for this debate :).This is a debate that could go either way as to my position, and I do believe that the world is going in both directions.More in the later rounds, thanks for the debate :).</t>
    <h>Is the world changing for the better (pro for better con for not)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="363" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  More new nations and peoples gaining a homeland some conflicts are being resolvedthe new generation is making a name for itself technolgy is booming. </t>
    <h>Is the world changing for the better (pro for better con for not)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="364" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes, we are at an all time low, but that doesn't mean Co2 levels aren't increasing [1]:  I would like to point out that global warming doesn't mandate warming all throughout Earth's life.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="365" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is unclear whether global warming is increasing hurricane frequency but there is increasing evidence that warming increases hurricane intensity.'Also, apologies for writing Carbon Dioxide as Co2.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="366" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Now once again if we look at this chart we can see that the gasses that are these Warming gasses and compare it to how much mankind has contributed to the Warming equation. </t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="367" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I give you the above graph measuring the past 600 million years of CO2 levels are we are actually at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="368" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We may observe that humans release approximately 35 gigatons of CO2 a year.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="369" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  The greenhouse effect on Planet Earth has been occurring for almost its whole life and is a natural phenomenon, since greenhouse gases such as Co2 have existed on Earth from its birth, thus heating the Earth to help sustain forms of life.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="370" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Global Warming: The state of which the Earth's temperature progressively and abnormally rises, which is attributed to the Greenhouse Effect that is caused by increased levels of carbon dioxide, other greenhouse gases, and pollutants in general.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="371" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="372" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    From this round I will refer to Carbon Dioxide as CO2.Also, my round 2 sites are incorrectly entered.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="373" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have to forfeit here as my friend is in the hospital with Leukemia and I've been busy with him and making sure he's alright.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming, on Planet Earth, Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="374" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con is literally claiming that because artificial reefs have the qualities of an artificial breakwater that they actually are artificial breakwaters.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="375" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro has never claimed that this is policy debate   (From the Government agency rebuttal) 1.) The plan will be carried out through Normal Means, Just as Every Single Policy Debate Plan Is.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="376" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    COST A.) Cost of the plan itselfCon has claimed the the price of the plan will be somewhere around 9% of the GDP using his personal calculations.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="377" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Let's try and begin here:Fairness Cons claim 1.) </t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="378" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Case offense answers Hurts biodiversity   Cost The pro's claim that the demand by con to protect their case rather than amend it during a debate is invalid.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="379" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    AnalyticsCostState protectionTrade disadvantageAnalyticsThe fact that the plan was premed does not excuse a lack of familiarity with the subject by the affirmative.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="380" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Every single objection brought up in the last round was fundementally logically deficent, pushed hypocritical terms, limited the round educationally made an inumerable amount of hasty generalizaitons among other logical fallacies and debased this entire debate.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="381" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In summation:Pro dropped Cost disad.Pro dropped State Protection disad.Pro dropped Trade disad.Con negated Tourism/Fishery advantage.Con dropped medical benefits disad.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="382" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> In this debate we will simply examine wether the USFG should implement Artificial Coral reefs on its coast lines.We will debate on the standard and accepted rules:1. </t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="383" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The flow of the debate will be as follows: Inherencies with the plan Analytics DA – Cost DA – Fails to protect states DA – Blocks ships   Analytics </t>
    <h>Resolved: The USFG should increase construction of mineral accretion coral reefs in the US</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="384" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Due to chemistry, we have learnt about and also discovered new elements, some of which are helpful to mankind and some which that aren't.</t>
    <h>Chemistry is the worst enemy of environment</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="385" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Chemistry is not exactly the worst enemy of the environment.</t>
    <h>Chemistry is the worst enemy of environment</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="386" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Environment is a combination of biological phenomenon,chemical consequences,applied mathematics and physics.so saying chemistry is the worst enemy not acceptable.</t>
    <h>Chemistry is the worst enemy of environment</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="387" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    May I also point out my opponent has already conceded to a rise in temperature from 1979-1998.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="388" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> As is shown, practically all of the major temperature recording studios agree on the temperature change. </t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="389" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    the Drudge Report, if you don't know what that is it is an uncensored news website that tells the truth and inst being choked by the government.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="390" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   How have we come to be told that global temperatures have suddenly taken a great leap upwards to their highest level in 1,000 years?</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="391" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> To clarify, I am NOT debating whether global warming isgood or bad for the Earth.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="392" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The problem with that argument is that we experienced the bulk of that warming between 1979 and 1998 .</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="393" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All I have sen in this debate from my opponent is information from sites that i am quite familiar with.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="394" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I extend all arguments.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="395" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has dropped every single point of mine, including the points that show global warming is real due to land and sea temperatures.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="396" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    global warming fake or real.</t>
    <h>global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="397" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The study of ice cores from Greenland from 1000 years back show that there was less CO2 production than today.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is killing us</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="398" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A 2003 study by researchers at the Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics shows temperatures from 1000-1100 AD (before fossil fuel use) that are comparable to those from 1900-1990.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is killing us</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="399" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming and cooling has occurred at periodic levels throughout the history of planet Earth.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is killing us</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="400" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The climate change that is happening from the past decades and the effects that grow rapidly in the present are quite alarming to many people.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is killing us</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="401" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has forfeited.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is killing us</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="402" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If you understand climate you should realize there are much more aspects to our atmosphere than CO2 caused by humans .</t>
    <h>Global Warming is mostly natural and a waste of our time and money to stop it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="403" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Let's start this off lightly with one argument:If global warming does not occur, then why has the rate of CO2 rose so fastly, out of the ordinary, completely unaffected by climate changes.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is mostly natural and a waste of our time and money to stop it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="404" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    What a shame.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is mostly natural and a waste of our time and money to stop it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="405" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote me.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is mostly natural and a waste of our time and money to stop it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="406" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Veganism is a way of living which seeks to exclude, as far as is possible and practicable, all forms of exploitation of, and cruelty to, animals for food, clothing or any other purpose.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="407" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    His baby is, after all, made of meat like animals.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="408" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Herbivores have molars to easily chew vegetables, and carnivores have K-9 teeth (the pointy teeth, for those of you who don't know what that means) to help tear meat.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="409" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     BoP is shared 10,000 Character Max 72 Hour argument time Open voting Open to anyone  Pro MUST argue in round 1, and Pro cannot argue in round 5  Pro: Vegan lifestyle is better.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="410" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Due to me doing a lot of things and having a busy schedule, I will not be able to post this round.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="411" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you Con for presenting your arguments.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="412" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Animals are still LOVED, they are not viewed as 'mere commodities'.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="413" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Have we had any problems eating animals.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="414" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you Con for this debate.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="415" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extending arguments.</t>
    <h>A Vegan lifestyle is better than a meat-eating one</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="416" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We do not have to live eternally to see the effects of global warming.</t>
    <h>Models of Climate Change and weather forcasts are equally wrong, most often.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="417" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In ancient times, like when subways were invented, the idea was to allow freedom of movement even when there was a big snowstorm.</t>
    <h>Models of Climate Change and weather forcasts are equally wrong, most often.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="418" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Climate change is a religion, as we will not be alive to see the truth of the predictions.</t>
    <h>Models of Climate Change and weather forcasts are equally wrong, most often.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="419" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Putting the subways aside; no it is not always that the weather forecasts are exact, but they are very often right.</t>
    <h>Models of Climate Change and weather forcasts are equally wrong, most often.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="420" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I can't hear you.</t>
    <h>Models of Climate Change and weather forcasts are equally wrong, most often.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="421" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> 'Whether humans' ability to think clearly and rationally is objectively great, there is no 'common good' when it comes to inter-species contact.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="422" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     My opponent has said that Earth has thrown so much at the human race and we have survived.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="423" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, this argument still stands.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="424" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Clarification: This debate is on the basis of whether or not humans are better than animals in respect to development and utilization of the environment, i.e.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="425" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    David Graber, an environmentalist at the National Parks Dept.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="426" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     When I said that I will not debate global warming, I meant right here, right now.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="427" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The 'innovators' such as my opponent ignore the fact that other living beings exist.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="428" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All my arguments above still apply here, as my opponent has forfeited this round.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="429" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent started with a quote from an environmentalist basically saying that humans have to be wiped out.</t>
    <h>Humans are better than animals</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="430" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    These solar cycles average eleven years in length, and they have ranged in length from nine years to beyond eighteen years.“</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="431" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Solar cycle as a driver of climate   It is good that Roy discards the idea that TSI can explain the modern temperature increase.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="432" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A study published in Science reviewed the ISI web of science in order to take a survey of relevant climate literature as to what the causes of climate change are.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="433" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    AGW Models fail, so the theory is wrongWe have agreed on a couple of basic points of climate science: 1.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="434" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In terms of this debate, man-made factors to climate change would be the emission of greenhouse gasses.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="435" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="436" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    AGW exists, it but doesn't dominate climate Greenhouse gases cause warming, and I never claimed otherwise.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="437" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Even though CO2 is the dominant climate driver of modern climate-change, it does not mean natural climate variability cannot occur in the system—it does occur.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is Man-Made</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="438" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank TylerGraham95 for this truly excellent debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="439" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In this round, I will post arguments against an anthropogenic cause to the recent global warming, and also consider as much as I can of my opponent's argument.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="440" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> What I am going to do is set up the basis of a cause effect relationship between greenhouse gases and a warming trend, and then confirm this relationship with corroborating corollaries.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="442" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is only natural to expect that fluctuations in the climate can be determined by the amount of solar activity.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="443" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>CO2 Lag in temperature changesSo the first problem we should address with this rebuttal is that it implies that I am trying to prove that GHGs are the driving force behind all forms of climate change.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="444" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is going to be one debate in a project I have devised to decide on the global warming issue once and for all - I will take the pro side in one debate, the con side in another debate, and make my decision from there.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="445" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this challenge and I accept all of my opponents rules and definitions.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is Not the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="446" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     ' Without technology, mankind would still be considered as animals trapped on a planet, unarmed and unfit to fight for survival and unable to complete even the simplest tasks.</t>
    <h>Technology brings more good than harm</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="447" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     As I have mentioned earlier, I have stated that technology is crucial to the survival of all living creatures.</t>
    <h>Technology brings more good than harm</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="448" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Harm of the industrial-technological society on Animals.</t>
    <h>Technology brings more good than harm</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="449" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Technology, is used around the globe, from the invention of wheels to the futuristic Google glasses.</t>
    <h>Technology brings more good than harm</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="450" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote con.</t>
    <h>Technology brings more good than harm</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="451" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have boobs.So do you.Since we are both male, it seems that you are trying to argue that mine are bigger than yours.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="452" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    they fired me for calling each customer a communist ;_;COMMIES!I looked in my backyard and saw what kind of looked like a squirrel.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="453" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'WTF' doesn't even mean 'What the f*ck' it means WHERE'S THE FOOD?!?!?!I even have my own t-shirt for this :D (http://skreened.com...)Did you know 'Dammit I'm Mad' is the same spelled backwards.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="454" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    5 rounds of all randomness.Rules:1.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="455" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Good luck.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="456" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    https://encrypted-tbn2.gstatic.com...Oh wait, I forgot I have bigger TITS THAN YOU :DPotatoes are my favorite food ever.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="457" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If you make fun of him, you make fun of everyone else on Earth!I'll give you a nickel if you tickle my pickle.Haha just kidding dude.Did you just notice the font change.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="458" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Never mind. Because of you I never stray too far from the sidewalk...Wait.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="459" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   You never find the answers if you throw your life awayAnd now.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="460" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> And that is why my opponent has bigger boobs than me.</t>
    <h>TROLL DEBATE: The Most Random Argument wins!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="461" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I want to establish, first, that this isn't a debate about Global Warming, but about Man-Made Global Warming.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="462" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     == Case ==  Contention 1: Human-caused global warming exists  The International Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) is an international group of some of the world’s most respected scientists.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="463" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It's up to the voters to decide if a team has gone too far and is not protected by this ruleTeam Mikal:- Mikal- Bluesteel- 16kadamTeam Global:- Donald.Keller- Lannan13- Subutai Round 1: Acceptance.Round 2: Arguments.Round 3: Arguments and Rebuttals.Round 4: Rebuttals and Closing Statements.**No new contentions on Round 4.**.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="464" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First, according to the greenhouse effect, global warming should be starting from the lower atmosphere and moved to the surface (because the CO2 collects in the upper troposphere first).</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="465" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    R1) Anthropogenic Global Warming (AGW) ExistsRight from the start we can see a lot of errors from Con’s opening arguments and graphs.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="467" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    C1Our opponents argue that tropospheric warming is minimal and that no hotspot exists.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="468" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend arguments  And thanks to our opposition for trying their best.</t>
    <h>GLOBAL WARMING: A Team Debate.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="469" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I recently saw a statistic that 1 in 4 Americans were skeptical of global warming and its damage to the world.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="470" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I give you the above graph measuring the past 600 million years of CO2 levels are we are actually at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="471" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    thus the massive amount of Co2 drops that range from super volcano explosions from Yosemite national park or other cataclysmic events that caused the death of millions of plants and thus a spike in Co2 levels.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="472" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent argues stating that the graphs of millions of years ago doesn't matter, but it does, because if the harms of Global Warming that my opponent says are true then we currently wouldn't be here.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="473" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     And in relation to your graphs that earth is heading towards a cooing era the measurements used to take them were provably ground based temperature readers that tend to vary widely.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="474" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> You have provided one graph while I have provided several that say the same thing done by different sources and not NASA and the EPA which can be bias to your case.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="475" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And the hypothesis that the WHO presented does not account for CFC's that are being made in china and India And in relation to the fact that water account for the greenhouse effect than other greenhouse gases is correct.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="476" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My first graph was showing the CO2 spike that Pro may be refuring to is from massive plant extintion and not from CO2 emmissions.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="477" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  If steps are not taken to reduce the emission of green house gases and other destructive chemicals that cause acceleration of the greenhouse effect the climate will progressively grow hotter and will lead to further drought.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="478" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept, please state your case.</t>
    <h>Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="479" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Second of all, very many oil companies would go out of business, causing an absolute crash of the US economy.</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="480" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Also, there are gasoline cars that are more gas efficient.</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="481" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Which leads to Global Warming, which is terrible for human kind, AND melts the ice caps, which can lead to polar bears and penguins having nowhere to live in the North or South poles!</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="482" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Dear con, many oil companies would go out of business.</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="483" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As for gas being cheaper than electric, bikes are far cheaper, and even motorcycles are cheaper.</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="484" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No oil company would go out of business.</t>
    <h>US Government should ban gas cars</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="485" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   'This shows that the advancement of medicine has not necessarily made lives better, in fact, it could be said that, although more people now survive diseases, their quality of life is lower.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="486" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Less people dieAs modern medicine is improving, less people die by disease.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="487" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Nowadays we have alternative options availible.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="488" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming does not exist EuthanasiaMy opponent asserts that: 'enthusiana was the only treatment availible during olden days.' This statement is incorrect.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="489" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The world: earth as a planet, societies in all the countries that exist todayBetter: towards a positive directionRound one acceptanceNo semantic arguments.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="490" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I dost accept.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="491" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    He does not look at the bigger picture, at the general decline from year 1000 to modern time, or even from millions of years ago to now, there has been the similar pattern regardless of CO2 emissions.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="492" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> I have not dropped any of my opponents arguments, instead I have flipped them on their head, proving that the things that he paints in a positive light are, in fact, more negative than positive.</t>
    <h>On Balance the World is Changing for the Better</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="493" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I give you the above graph measuring the past 600 million years of CO2 levels are we are actually at an all time low.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="494" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is significantly man man made  Here is a general website that debunks anti man made global warming folks, claim by claim.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="495" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rules Round 1 is for definitions by Con while Pro will make her opening arguments.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="496" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    When it comes to scientists there are a total of 2,500 scientists that do believe in Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="497" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Contention 6: Global Warming Public Opinion First off, in a recent poll in the United States showed that 53% of Americans do not believe in Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="498" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    98% of scientists agree with me.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="499" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     plus 98% of scientists agree with me.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
   <pair id="500" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    now con resorts to making up facts about the beliefs of scientists.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Man-made Global Warming Exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="501" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Global warming: a gradual increase in the overall temperature of the earth's atmosphere.Greenhouse effect: the trapping of the sun's warmth in a planet's lower atmosphere.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="502" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Graph F displays the rapid increase of carbon dioxide levels.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="503" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     If we observe the above graph we can see that Earth has been a whole lot hotter than where we currently are to the point where the Earth's average temperature has been 7.5 degrees Celcuis hotter than it currently it is.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="504" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Contention 1: CO2 increase from humans  My opponent states that CO2 levels have never been this high, but that is incorrect.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="505" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Round 1This debate is about global warming, and whether or not is a real phenomenon.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="506" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this debate.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="507" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Instead, we have been presented a point of view, which is axiomatic of the anti-climate change position.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="508" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Let me explain, an ice age goes through two phases.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="509" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Round One: Respond ONLY with 'I accept' or you will be thrown out of the debate.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="510" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="511" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent concedes that man-made global warming is, in fact, real.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="512" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm away at the moment, and my opponent may be busy.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="513" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     The case is found to be resolved in the negative.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="514" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I feel disrespected and am backing out of this debate.</t>
    <h>Man-Made Global Warming is a Hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="515" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Definition:  Cult leader: 'The leader of a system of veneration and devotion directed towards a particular figure or object'.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="516" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept, sure - I'm quite a big Molyneux fan.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="517" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It can be seen that Stefan is open to differing opinions, and respects them if they are presented in a calm and non-aggressive manner.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="518" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No tolerance for questions or critical inquiry.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="519" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  'Physicists kind of [expletive] me off, 'cause they've always got their [expletive] pale hands in my goddamn wallet, and stealing from my child's future, indebting her.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="520" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm sorry, I've lost completely all motivation to do this debate.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="521" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ok, not sure how to respond to that but sure.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="522" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All points to PRO.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="523" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Full forfeit.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="524" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ok.</t>
    <h>Stefan Molyneux is a Cult Leader</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="525" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      Proposition One: Carbon Dioxide Release from Multiple Sources    Global warming has been allegedly caused by an excess of Co2 release from the ocean and multiple other sources.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="526" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Next, my opponent addresses the CO2 concentrations and shows a little cloud diagram.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="527" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Accordingly to the Industrial Revolution/Co2 release correlation graph, we can see that the Co2 release has gone outside the main tenants of the normal Co2 equilibrium.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="528" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You have a good argument, and it is truly disgusting what humans are doing to this Earth, BUT they are not the cause of global warming, as I will argue.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="529" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that global warming is not significantly impacted by human activity, and my opponent will be arguing that humans are the cause/have a big effect on global warming.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="530" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Although both propositions are true, and is not normally debated; the complete defense of the first proposition is enough for the opponent’s BoP to not be fulfilled.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is not significantly affected by human activity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="531" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>As described in [8], Von Storch systematically ran all the IPCC computer models of the climate, and found that the actual temperatures for the last 17 years fell outside the model predictions.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="532" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    CO2 has increased by 54% in past 17 years with no global warming, and CO2 theory cannot explain whyNASA data, which I cited in [6], shows there has been no global warming for 17 years.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="533" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Correlation plus a theory is not proof CO2 dominates climateMy opponent noted temperature generally rising since 1900 and CO2 rising since 1900, and claims that because CO2 is a greenhouse gas, it must be responsible for the rise.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="534" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Since 2000, CO2 has risen by 54% with no increase in global temperatures.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="535" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The United States alone has a crude oil energy output of 19,420,000,000,000,000 British Thermal Units [6].</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="536" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Anomalies are deviations from 'schedule' weather cycles, and can include both hot and cold extremes, making 'global warming' only half of this discussion.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="537" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First round, acceptance.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="538" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="539" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There has been no global warming for 17 years, despite a 54% increase in CO2 Pro now argues there is something wrong with NASA's Remote Sensing Satellite (RSS) data [6] because it does not measure temperature with a thermometer.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="540" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Pro's initial contention was that vanishing Arctic sea ice proves that CO2 dominates climate.'</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Climate Change Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="541" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will argue (as con) that global warming does not exist.'  The topic is 'Global Warming Exists.'  Since this, so formulated, is totally open-ended I will state some definitions.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="542" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will start by thanking the CON side for their response.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="543" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I apologize ahead of time if my arguments are few in number and cover few grounds.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="544" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    1) There hasn't been any global warming since 1997: If nothing changes in the next year, we're going to have kids who graduate from high school who will have never seen any 'global warming' during their lifetimes.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="545" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     1) There hasn't been any global warming since 1997: If nothing changes in the next year, we're going to have kids who graduate from high school who will have never seen any 'global warming' during their lifetimes.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="546" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has forfeited two rounds.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="547" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro may use their first round, but not round 5.</t>
    <h>Global warming exists.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="548" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The idea of carbon sinking is that you store the CO2 in some medium, such as trees.</t>
    <h>Planting Excess Trees is a Good Practices</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="549" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  * Relationship Between Animals (wild) and Humans : In this case, animals are considered to be wild. </t>
    <h>Planting Excess Trees is a Good Practices</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="550" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Areas affected by this need excessive reforestation to deal with the massive decline of nutrients in the soil.</t>
    <h>Planting Excess Trees is a Good Practices</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="551" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Dear readers,  Today I stand against the topic 'Planting Excess Trees Is A Good Practice'.</t>
    <h>Planting Excess Trees is a Good Practices</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="552" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I am NOT arguing that Obama was a perfect president, I will express points that prove that he handled many situations well and passed some good policy.</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="553" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First round is acceptance.My stance: Obama doesn't deserve all the hate he gets.</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="554" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    While I believe Obama does suck as a president, I would like to entertain the ideas that he does not do so that bad, while providing as many of the ways he does as I can :).</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="556" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     In your argument, you brought three issues that you believe Obama has handled quite well, that removes him from the 'sucks' category: Civil rights, education, and environment.</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="557" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In an effort to maintain a fair and equal debate, I will forgo this round, and we will (should) move directly into rebuttals in the final round.</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="558" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am giving my opponent a chance to express their round 2 arguments, as stated in the comments.</t>
    <h>Compared to most politicians, Obama is an okay president</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="559" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Framework Pro will argue that Bernie Sanders should be the next president, whilst Con will argue that Rand Paul should be the next president.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="560" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm going to mostly spend this round to build my own case, largely because I run low on characters and CON hasn't offered any arguments, but has merely stated several of Paul's positions.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="561" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that Rand Paul should be the next United States president instead of Bernie Sanders.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="562" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hopefully we can debate this at some time on the future; I had a stockpile of sources piling up in a Word file and was on the brink of running out of characters lol.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="563" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am too busy this week for a long debate like this.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="564" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'll keep posting.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="565" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="566" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No problem.</t>
    <h>Bernie Sanders versus Rand Paul</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="567" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    first round is for acceptance -.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="568" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="570" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent has not made a single argument for his position or a refutation of my arguments.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="571" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, most of my opponent's arguments either deals with the existence of global warming itself, or rules out (rather invalidly) other alternatives.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="572" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Human produced greenhouse gases will continue to accumulate in the atmosphere causing climate change because the earth's forests, oceans, and other 'carbon sinks' cannot adequately absorb them all.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="573" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And as always, thanks for debating.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="574" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank my opponent for this debate as well, although he doesn't address any of the concerns I had with his arguments or his own arguments' relevancy.</t>
    <h>That Humans Are Causing Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="575" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First, is global warming actually happening.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="576" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Well from the satilight.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="577" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We are not debating about the 70s or global cooling.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="578" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Back in the 70's there was a big scare about global cooling.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="579" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I don't know what to say since you didn't respond.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Exists</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="580" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Direct sunlight, cosmic rays, magnetic fields, short and long term solar cycles, all easily explain--and contribute--to climate change [7].</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="581" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Observational evidence contradicts the positive feedback cloud assumption that the IPCC and others assume, making it very unlikely that greenhouse gasses have caused significant warming in the 20th century [1].</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="582" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I previously cited a source that reliably stated that the climate was actually more sensitive towards CO2 due to positive feedbacks than it was towards solar causes.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="583" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      The fact is, the direct effect from man-made gases cannot, alone, cause climate change.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="584" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Without greenhouse gases, it is speculated that the earth would freeze.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="585" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will argue that CO2 is the largest contribution to global warming, at 72% [1] of greenhouse gas emissions, and that greenhouse gas emissions are a major contributor to global warming.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="586" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Accepted.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="587" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Correct: Accurate  Rules:  First round is acceptance, round 2 is for arguments, 3 is for rebuttals.</t>
    <h>Anthropogenic Global Warming Theory is Correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="588" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First round is for acceptance ONLY.</t>
    <h>The gas powered car was the worst invention ever.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="589" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>The gas powered car was the worst invention ever.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="590" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Humanity is a pathetic species. We must reform our society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="591" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    To uphold the resolution you must first show that P1 is true.</t>
    <h>Humanity is a pathetic species. We must reform our society.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="592" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The ideas were points suggested in the form of rhetorical questions:1) If communists also use natural resources amp; pollute the environment - then - obviously - Capitalism is not the only economic system which does.And I in no way suggested that Capitalism is 'universal' amp; humans' inherent need to consume automatically leads to it.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="593" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Honestly, we simply ran out of time to give it a good once over - and I felt addressing the environment, amorality and utility were more important first, which leads to addressing the Working Class.Alex, I will touch on the Working Class just so we can say we did - however, voters can disregard.Pro' Closing Statement Concerns:Issue of the Morality of CapitalismThe argument often used for the morality of Capitalism is Utility.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="594" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con is in no way obligated to follow suit.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="595" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We are governed by the Laws of Thermodynamics and there is no way of escaping this.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="596" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Capitalism destroys the environment.Capitalism is without a doubt the most productive economic system ever created.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="597" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   So the problem isn't Capitalism. </t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="598" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   I will remind the voters that Capitalism is not an universal to all of history and is not the defacto system of life.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="599" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Capitalism is not inherently bad 2.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="600" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Economic system in which most of the means of production are privately owned, and production is guided and income distributed largely through the operation of markets.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="601" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I accept your debate and challenge.</t>
    <h>Capitalism is Immoral</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="602" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Round 3-Paragraph 2 amp; 3: Beachapedia.org  In rd.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="603" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Fracking should NOT be entirely banned within the sovereign territory (including bodies of water) of the United States.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="604" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I stand corrected, although I did provide information behind the reason for fracking to be banned onshore (consider it an extension, showing problems which arise from onshore fracking also), there are still unjustifiable environmental implications which arise from offshore hydraulic fracturing.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="605" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Environmental Protection Agency that 70 to 140 billion gallons of water was used to fracture 35,000 wells in the United States each year.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="606" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I reserve the right to argue in favor of not banning it while increasing regulations and restrictions on the practice, in addition to better enforcement of current laws.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="607" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am for Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing to be banned.</t>
    <h>Offshore Hydraulic Fracturing (Fracking) - Should it be banned?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="608" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Man-Made Global Warming exists.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="609" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Outline:Most of Pro's case is focused on CO2.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="610" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Points Ceded by Con-GHGs are at an all time high-Humans do emit large quantities of GHGs (which he claims is too small in proportion to general emissions)-The ocean is losing its ability to absorb GHGsDefencesI.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="611" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Man contributes to global warming in more ways than just producing greenhouse gases.The greenhouse gamut of gasesMan produces more than just CO2 grenhouse gases.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="612" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con's case:Premise 1: Global Warming PotentialWhat few people realize about things like Green House Gas is that they are not all born equal.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="613" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The BOP is shared.For the sake of this debate, Pro must argue that Mankinds interference with nature is a significant cause of the general upward trend of average global temperatures.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="614" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Definitions:  GWP (Global Warming Potential) = The total effect on Global Warming per ppm.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="615" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Outline: With most of Pro's argument based off the effect of CO2, I simply have to show that CO2 has a minor effect on Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="616" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Final Defense:Defense 1: Global Warming Potential of CO2The Global Warming Potential of CO2 is, simply said, weak.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="617" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The cambrian era likely had a lower level of climate sensitivity.(B) Man Made CO2I've stated that CO2 'tips the pot' and proved it.</t>
    <h>Man-Made global warming exists* and poses a serious threat to humanity.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="618" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    i guess i agree with taking actions to slowly change but i dont think we should stop drilling until we completly drill it all up.</t>
    <h>Redo: Global Warming is real and we ought to do something about it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="619" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The last time I tried doing this I made the time way to short I accidently took to long to post my answer and it said I had dropped out so lets do this again.</t>
    <h>Redo: Global Warming is real and we ought to do something about it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="620" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Because I wasn't imformed you accepted I am very sorry.</t>
    <h>Redo: Global Warming is real and we ought to do something about it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="621" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    i gotta be honest with you i unstood nothing of what you just said.</t>
    <h>Redo: Global Warming is real and we ought to do something about it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="622" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    you do a redo but yet you dont rebut my argument.</t>
    <h>Redo: Global Warming is real and we ought to do something about it</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="623" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks for accepting this debate I hope we have a great debate.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="624" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Developed countries do not have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="625" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  However, Global warming could cost the world up to $20 trillion over two decades for cleaner energy sources and do the most harm to people who can least afford to adapt, U.N.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="626" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend all Arguments.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="627" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend All Arguments.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="628" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    THESIS: The mean surface temperature of the Earth has risen by 0.74±0.18 °C over the period 1906–2012.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="629" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The results of their study showed that the hockey stick curve happened as a result from poor data handling, obsolete data, and incorrect calculation of principal components [1].</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="630" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As a kind of shorthand, some scientists refer to the graphed geometry of this peak as a 'hockey stick' to evoke a rapid rise after a sustained period of less dramatic change.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="631" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     In this debate we will be arguing whether or not the famous hockey stick graph is likely (greater than 50%) correct.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="632" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That's too bad.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="633" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I forgot about this debate so vote pro.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="634" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks to Con for the sportsmanlike gesture.</t>
    <h>Resolved: The Hockey Stick is likely correct</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="635" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have nothing to say because my opponent forfeited.</t>
    <h>Developing countries should prioritize environmental protection over resource extraction</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="636" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Same thing.</t>
    <h>Developing countries should prioritize environmental protection over resource extraction</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="637" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Arbor states, http://www.treesaregood.com.</t>
    <h>Developing countries should prioritize environmental protection over resource extraction</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="638" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I negate, Resolved: Developed countries should prioritize environmental protection over resource extraction when the two are in conflict.</t>
    <h>Developing countries should prioritize environmental protection over resource extraction</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="639" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes we should even though its not going to start happening until too late we really should.</t>
    <h>We ALL Should Do Something About Global Warming. Because It's Creating An Ice-Age As Well.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="640" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Round 3: Refutation of opponents argument 'This is a graph of CO2 concentrations and global temperature.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="641" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'In the previous graph which covers 450,000 years, we see the exact same relationship between Co2 and temperature' This statement is false.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="642" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A sudden rise in temperature and Co2 on each peak.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="643" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It has also been shown here that conspiracy theories are riddled throughout arguments provided by denialists.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="644" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Resolved: Ice Ages are real, we are currently in an interglacial period and the Earth will warm further with or without the influences of mankind.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="645" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is a graph of CO2 concentrations and global temperature.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="646" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Round 1: acceptance only Round 2: opening arguments (Thou shall not refute current round) Round 3: refutation of opponent's Round 2 argument.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="647" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Ice Ages versus Man Made Climate Change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="648" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Factories worldwide are responsible for releasing pollutants like carbon monoxide, sulphur dioxide, nitrogen oxides etc into the atmosphere which is the prime reason why the ozone layer is depleting.</t>
    <h>Did peace is connected to good environment?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="649" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    too much peace is bad thing.</t>
    <h>Did peace is connected to good environment?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="650" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    because with chaos the no drive.</t>
    <h>Did peace is connected to good environment?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="651" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Current weather modification programs should be banned because cloud seeding is a toxic, inadequate and unpredictable solution that may have disastrous consequences.</t>
    <h>Weather modification programs affect the climate and should be banned.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="652" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    On the topic of not underestimating the ecological crisis in comparison with the economic crisis.Firstly, I would like to point out the length of the ecological cris in comparison with the economic crisis.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="653" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    climate change, should be focused on more than the economic crisis.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="654" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Good luck to the opponent; serious entries only please :)  Round 1 - Acceptance and introduction of your position Round 2 - First arguments Round 3 - Rebuttal Round 4 - Personal conclusion  As stated, my position is that the ecological crisis deserves more attention than the economical crisis.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="655" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  To the contrary, we should the economy going again before we focus on the ecological crisis, and in this debate I will work to prove this.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="656" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I made clear that my reason for not providing a suggested solution for the economic crisis is that that is another debate because there are so many options.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="657" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Con's statement that a economic crisis can be solved quicker than an ecological crisis is ofcourse valid.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="658" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank my opponent for his arguments.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="659" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Next, Pro suggests that I said that the ecological crisis is not here yet.</t>
    <h>The ecological crisis should be more focused on than the economic crisis.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="660" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Utilitarianism is not a self-consistent moral system because utilitarianism is not moral in the first place.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="661" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This debate is about whether utilitarianism is a system that is consistent within itself.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="662" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    So both these examples show the immorality of utilitarianism.'  You just completely ignored the definitions of 'moral system' I posted.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="663" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'You just completely ignored the definitions of 'moral system' I posted.'  I did not ignore the definition of moral system my opponent posted.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="664" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'I specified in my opening that when I said 'utilitarianism' I referred to maximizing happiness while also reducing suffering.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="665" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Utilitarianism is not a self-consistent moral system because utilitarianism is not moral in the first place.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="666" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     'How does this relate to utilitarianism?'  This was just a lead in to the rest of the paragraph; it was never meant to be part of the debate.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="667" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The point is that you are saying that utilitarianism is not a consistent moral system because it doesn't make a statement on a circumstance where neither course of action is inherently more moral.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="668" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Hitler, although he was not a moral person, he was an amazing orator which is how he convinced many people that Jews were less than them.'</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="669" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will not be attacking in this round because it would be unfair to my opponent since he is unable to respond.</t>
    <h>Utilitarianism is a self-consistent moral system</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="670" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Please tell me what you think.</t>
    <h>When Will Global Warming Become Strong Enough To Actually Inflict Harm To The Animals And People On Earth?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="671" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My answer to that question is no.</t>
    <h>There is currently an enviromental crisis in the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="672" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In this case, Con is not calmly stating a defensible argument.</t>
    <h>There is currently an enviromental crisis in the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="673" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your graphs and evidence in your constructive seems to be missing.</t>
    <h>There is currently an enviromental crisis in the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="674" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
    <t>Google Maps Coordinates, showing deforestation' /gt;37.800832,-81.841133 Google Maps Coordinates, showing Massive deforestation Perhaps most horrifying, the human toll is almost unimaginable. </t>
    <h>There is currently an enviromental crisis in the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="675" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I showed that there is at least one important environmental crisis occuring in the United States, and that environmental concerns remain relevant.</t>
    <h>There is currently an enviromental crisis in the United States</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="676" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Please provide some links that will provide information on the number of vehicles per household in Nippon and Indonesia and the laws effect on traffic.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="677" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Singapore does not limit the number of vehicles per household.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="678" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The reason why I can say if we limit the number of vihicel in very household in a country, it can decrease the traffic jam in a country who legalize this programe.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="679" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    because they know the impact if teh number of vihicle in they country increase extremly.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="680" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have a data about a country who run this programme like Japan (Nippon).</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="681" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    So, there is no change except life would be more complicated for members of a household.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="682" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First is that limiting the number of vehicles per household will reduce traffic.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="683" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm Toharu from Indonesia and I believe we should limit the number of vihicle(s) in every household.</t>
    <h>THW Limit the numer of vihicle(s) in every household</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="684" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I need data about why some people are for and some are against global warming.</t>
    <h>For Or Against Global Warming And Why</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="685" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
    <t>Design = creation. </t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="686" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> 1) Evolution and life are too complex to have happened by mere chance and 2) Creationism (in the Bible) is logical as it fills in all the gaps that evolution leaves out.</t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="687" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Evolution tries to teach that we came from a primordial soup of single celled organisms which changed and developed through a whole range of life-forms into what we are today.</t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="688" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank my opponent for this opportunity to debate, and I take the following side: Creationism isn't the most logical answer.</t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="689" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, it might have been for a very good reason.</t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="690" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
    <t>Allow me to narrow this down a bit further: '...design, indicating design'. </t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="691" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank my opponent for his arguments, refutes, and closing statements.</t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="692" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Is the thought that evolution happens by accident alone a fallacy? </t>
    <h>is creation the most logical answer?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="693" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Resolution: The human population has begun Overpopulation.Keypoints of this Debate:Deforestation.Food Supply.Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="694" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    One of the problems that we face is pollution, which global warming contributes to (14).</t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="695" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It's poor conduct to post well beyond the limit, and into the Comment Section.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="696" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
    <t>According to the UNEP Billion Trees Program, all the trees grown under the UN program equaled 2 billion in 18 months after launch. </t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="697" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In 2011, our population reached a record 7 billion.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="698" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote Con.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation: The Truth In Numbers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="699" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Trees.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="700" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    (b) This is good because you can feed that many people with just the land we are using for farms.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="701" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that Overpopulation is not, as of right now, a serious threat.I will let the Con provide her argument and sources first.</t>
    <h>Overpopulation</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="702" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The failure to make peace with the perceived enemy often chalks up, not our disability to make intellectual peace, but to make emotional war.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="703" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, at intense times, humans could pull their minds together and make rational decisions.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="704" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Throughout history, extremely intelligent men and women have made blunders, but that doesn't mean we lack intelligence.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="705" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Humans had been discovering about the universe and trying to build spaceships to go out and conquer other planets.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="706" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am looking forward to debating with whoever is willing to accept my challenge.Ps.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="707" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A very interesting subject that I am intrigued to debate you on.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="708" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Here we are, the final round of debating, and without a further ado;  1.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="709" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for your reply, and I too wish you luck for the final round;  1.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="710" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thanks my opponent for his thoughtful arguments.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="711" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If humans could control their emotions, life would be even more simple than drinking water or breathing itself.</t>
    <h>Humans are an intellectual beings.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="712" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Population Growth On average, 360 people are born each day with only 150,000 that die each day[1].</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="713" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Population Growth My opponent here says that birth rates have been on a decline within the past 12 years.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="714" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will be arguing that population growth is not the problem and that homosexuals do not help in the overall thriving of the Human species.Population GrowthI would like to focus the population Growth for the past 12 years.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="715" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    IntroductionI would thank my opponent as well.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="716" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The first round is for acceptance.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="717" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="718" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    IntroductionI thank my opponent for his response, however I am getting the feeling that he is not taking this debate very seriously.We Definitely Do Need Population ControlPoverty'1.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="719" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    While Homosexuals can't have children there are still straight people.</t>
    <h>Homosexuals Are An Asset To The Overall Thriving Of The Human Species</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="720" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Alright, it's a natural cycle FUELED or SPED UP by man.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="721" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Something that people are not so aware of with regards to global warming is the contribution of agriculture - which is to say livestock and farming - which is third in the world for CO2 emissions.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="722" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank JonMilne for accepting this debate.I.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="723" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    by Lucky Savings' href='#'gt;satellite and high-altitude balloon data confirm that the lower atmosphere is not trapping lots of additional heat due to higher CO2 concentrations.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="724" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All arguments must be visible inside this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="725" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I eagerly await my opponent's argument.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="727" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     'The Great Global Warming Swindle'  Much of my opponent's arguments basically borrows from ideas that haven't held up in a long while and are generally dismissed by the vast majority of climate change scientists.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="728" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank JonMilne for this great debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="729" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Not always.</t>
    <h>Even If You Don't Believe In Global Warming, You Should Still Go Green.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="730" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Just make sure it doesn't happen anywhere else.</t>
    <h>Even If You Don't Believe In Global Warming, You Should Still Go Green.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="731" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I defintiely agree because even if you don't believe in global warming because we defineitly need to leave a green legacy for the hundreds of future generations to come.</t>
    <h>Even If You Don't Believe In Global Warming, You Should Still Go Green.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="732" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First of all, I don't approve of the people that know the advantages of going green and choose to ignore it.</t>
    <h>Even If You Don't Believe In Global Warming, You Should Still Go Green.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="733" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    People are constantly using the explanation "global warming isn't real" to put off going green.</t>
    <h>Even If You Don't Believe In Global Warming, You Should Still Go Green.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="734" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     #1   http://www.geocraft.com.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="735" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Something that has been established or accepted by fraudulent means.global warmingn.An increase in the average temperature of the earth's atmosphere, especially a sustained increase sufficient to cause climatic change.I am going to argue that there is no such thing as global warming, or at least there is nothing valid that proves such a thing exists.No forfeits or concessions.Argument must be serious.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="736" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    i fully accept the conditions of my opponent and my position of the opponent i also will allow him to start the arguement.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="737" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As dust and sandstorms turn day into night across thousands of miles of former prairie, farmsteads, roads and even entire towns will be engulfed by sand.'</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="738" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> We still have the Co2 weight problem, the thermodynamic laws problem, the water vapor percentage and absorption problem, the history problem, the fraud problem, the corruption problem. </t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="739" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Leave the guy alone with the mega-bucks he earned, his oil company, and his gigantic carbon footprint.The Co2 ppm is meaningless until you explain how Co2 does Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="740" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And we also have an other set of logical fallacies...I can't but chuckle at how you called 'facts' 'fake'.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="741" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> before you start round 3 i recomend you watch an incoveinent truth also it is not global warming its climate change this is why some places get cooler and some get warmer. </t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="742" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    this website would be pretty stupid if everyone just called each other liars without proof  so.</t>
    <h>Global Warming is a hoax</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="743" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You eat the cows that are hurting the environment.</t>
    <h>Vegetarians Don't Help Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="744" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I've seen some evidence that suggested that we're actually at the end of an ice age and therefore the weather is warming up.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="745" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Due to many problems posting arguments for the last debate, Citrakayah and I have decided to restart the debate in order to iron out the structural problems of this debate and because the computer deleted my argument.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="746" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    right now) global warming.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="747" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The level of activity from the sun correlates with the average global temperature.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="748" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Sun  My opponent claims that solar activity has diverged from temperatures since the 1980s.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="749" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Sea Level RiseI don’t argue for an apocalypse where the ocean rises twenty feet.First I’d like to note that Tuvalu has an average elevation of about six feet above sea level.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="750" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ocean Currents  Ocean currents can't heat themselves, though.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="751" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    C1: Public Health Many disease-carrying organisms can live only in areas with specific temperatures.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="752" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept, and wish the best of luck to my opponent.</t>
    <h>Climate Change Is Not an Imminent Danger</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="753" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global Warming is a natural cycle, but it is always good to reduce our carbon footprint, just so we can ration our already dwindling supply of fossil fuels.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="754" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is a massive problem  If the rate continues Antarctica will melt quicker and then in the 23rd century(maybe maybe not) we will all be DEAD.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Problem</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="755" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The problem with this is that we can't come to an agreement with other countries, above all else, it's empirically proven that technology separates us from other parts of the world.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="756" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, the real problem lies in the actions the US and other countries do to 'provoke' terrorist peoples to use technology against us.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="757" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm new here as well, best of luck.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="758" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, some are saying it is ruining the essential qualities or 'peace' of life that they once enjoyed.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="759" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Well, this is my last round, and I will have no more to say after you post your final argument.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="760" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    But we're not losing just one animal, we're losing tons of animals at a fast rate.</t>
    <h>The advancement of Technology is Good</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="761" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Wake up, Rip Van Winkel.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="762" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming causes climate change.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="763" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   the Sun is now changing from its Solar Grand Maximum to its Solar Grand Minimum. </t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="764" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Temperature of Earth's Atmosphere Has Been Increasing Slightly, but No Longer Continues to IncreaseLooking at the bare temperature statistics, there has now been no net warming since 1997 - 15 years with CO2 rising with no global temperature increase.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="765" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No correlation with CO2 and temperature 2a.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="766" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank Magic8000 for accepting this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="767" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The sun is warming since other planets are warming.2.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="768" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks.'As said by Con, I will present my argumentsThe typical argument is like this [1]  The Earth's atmosphere keeps the planet much warmer than it would be without an atmosphere.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="769" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All arguments must be visible inside this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="770" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A question about R2 though, can I present my rebuttals in R2.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="771" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    More scientific and logical.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="772" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Supposedly global warming is a natural process that people didn't cause, but no, climate change is mostly  humans fault.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="773" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thnk its climate change - its more scientific and logical.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="774" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    CLimate CHange - more scientific and more logical.</t>
    <h>Its Climate Change Not Global Warming.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="775" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is a myththhh.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Problem</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="776" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> With the advent of sonograms and live-action ultrasound images, neonatologists and nurses are able to see unborn babies at 20 weeks gestation react physically to outside stimuli such as sound, light and touch.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="777" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Ecological ConcernsIn 2006, the United Nations calculated that the total climate-change emissions of animals bred for meat was 18% of the global total; this is more than cars, planes, and all other transportation combined.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="778" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ecological  You state, “1st water is a renuable resource and we shouldn't worry about whether or not it takes more water for a cow then wheat, because it is all going to be renewed and if we chose not to eat those cows they would consume more water to live longer.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="779" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Topic:A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="780" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept your debate, and just to be clear last round is just a sort of closing statement correct, if I am wrong please correct me in your 1st argument/statement.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="781" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for bringing up the “humane” options for meat.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="782" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I think if a person doesn't cause an animal pain before slaughter, kills it swiftly, and this action doesn't hurt any other person, there is nothing unethical about the consumption of the meat.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="783" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Personally, I don't think eating animal flesh is wrong in itself.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="784" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    1st no need to opologise we share some of the same beliefs like evolution in creation.</t>
    <h>A vegetarian diet is more ethical than a meat-eating diet</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="785" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Overpopulation is the root of many political conflicts and virtually all environmental problems.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="786" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The same goes for water.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="787" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I will try to keep this short because I have to wake up in 6 hours.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="788" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There will be more members who will defend and stay guard to protect their territory and their group.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="789" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Each year our population increases greatly but with that the demand for food, oil, electricity increases with it.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="790" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It would seem silly to repeat myself at length, so I will just distill it to the bare essentials:  - There are not too many humans, and there never will be.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="791" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thanks for debating.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="792" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have nothing to add until I have something to respond to.</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="793" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you, it was a pleasure :).</t>
    <h>Is overpopulation a world threat?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="794" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    So true.</t>
    <h>Instead Of Trying To Find Who Is To Blame For Climate Change We Should All Work Together To Solve The Problem.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="795" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    No points or arguments.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="796" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent claims I have 'contradicted' myself.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="797" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is actually a consensus in favor of global warming.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="798" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     I believe global warming is not real and any temperature change is caused by the sun.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="799" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You just countered your own argument.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="800" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am sorry but I refuse to debate this with you.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="801" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    But okay.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="802" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If we agree, we can ask airmax to close the debate.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="803" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am devils advocating this debate.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="804" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I think there is a lot of debate.</t>
    <h>Humans Cause Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="805" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Of course it's real.</t>
    <h>IS Global Warming Really An Issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="806" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I think people over-dramatize and exaggerate the problem.</t>
    <h>IS Global Warming Really An Issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="807" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Absolutely.</t>
    <h>IS Global Warming Really An Issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="808" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ...yes.</t>
    <h>IS Global Warming Really An Issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="809" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    What do you think of when you hear the words "global warming?" You might envision melting ice caps, drowning polar bears and shrinking coast lines.</t>
    <h>IS Global Warming Really An Issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="810" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rules: Round 1- introduction of argument and/or for acceptance Round 2- I refute your argument ornyou refute mine Round 3- We refute each other's Round 4- We refute each other's Round 5- closing arguments.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="811" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   What I will be arguing is that, all other things being held equal, the murder of a child is a worse thing to happen than that of an adult.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="812" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I never denied that I am supposed to debate that murder of children is worse than murder of adults.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="813" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Murder is murder.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="814" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    All my opponent did last round is argue that we're all going to die some day.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="815" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We have basically ruined the Earth.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="816" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Actually, in this debate, you were supposed to debate that murder of children IS worse than murder off adults because you are pro.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="817" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Murder is murder.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="818" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Murder of children is worse than murder of adults</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="819" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Do you think global warming is cause by the greenhouse effect.</t>
    <h>The Greenhouse Effect Causes Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="820" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>      My opponent’s arguments rely on three main contentions:   1)   Global warming is real and is a threat 2)   Global warming is caused by human activity 3)   We should attempt to stop global warming   I will refute them as follows:   1.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="821" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is real and is a threat      It was implied that there was global warming, because if there wasn’t this debate would be futile.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="822" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is a definite warming in specific parts of the world, [1] but there are also other areas with the same -- or even colder -- temperatures as when weather recording began in the U.S.A.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="823" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If you were born after February 1985, [1] you have never experienced a colder than average month.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="824" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Second, it is unlikely increasing CO2 has a large impact because CO2 increases are logarithmic, in other words the more CO2 there is the less warming effect each unit has.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="825" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Notice that there are more high temperature areas in the oceans and that they go farther North and South than the land masses do.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="826" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would also like to thank my opponent for this debate.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="827" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank 16kadams for a wonderful first debate, here at DDO.I also must admit that my opponent has put forth very valid arguments, some of which I greatly agree with.</t>
    <h>Taking a Stand Against Climate Change with Greener Technologies</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="828" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Life won't disapear when we reach the peak of global warming infact life will be at an all time high.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="829" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Introduction:The problem I and many others have with the Cato Institute is the fact that it allows special interest groups who fund it to hijack its message, even when that message is controversial.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="830" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'C1: Cato and Big Tobacco'1) I may have been a touch misleading here, and I apologize for any confusion I may have caused.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="831" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    C1: Cato and Big TobaccoPro's first claim is that Cato has received donations from 'Big Tobacco' and in return Pro alleges that the Institute tailored its content to reflect the interests of its donors.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="832" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Cato Institute (www.cato.org) is a influential American think tank, headquartered in Washington D.C.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="833" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="834" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    C1: Cato and Big Tobacco  1) Pro has changed his main argument from the thesis that Cato tailors it's content as a result of corporate donations to the thesis that the reason Cato exists originally is in order to forward corporate interests.</t>
    <h>The Cato Institute does not deserve respect or credibility</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="835" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     The concentration of carbon dioxide (CO2) in Earth's atmosphere has reached 395 ppm (parts per million) as of June 2012 and rose by 2.0 ppm/yr during 2000'2009.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="836" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The CON must prove humans do not play a significant role in global warming.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="837" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will assume that the first round is for acceptance since my opponent put forth minimal arguments and the BoP is on him.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="838" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    CO2 CorrelationFirst, what my opponent seems to fail to take into account, is that the Earth is in the middle of a 30-year cooling trend.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="839" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming has produced more CO2, rather than more CO2 producing global warming.'[1] My opponent uses an extremely zoomed out graph, making it hard to see this.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="840" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank jh12341 for presenting his arguments.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="841" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, he has failed to provide any correlation between CO2 and temperature; meaning that he has not proven how CO2 causes temperature increases.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="842" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     CO2 Correlation  The sunspots actually rose after the temperature in 1960, according to the chart from [A].</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="844" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Correlation between CO2 and Temperature  The records have shown strong correlations between climate and CO2 levels, as seen in the graph at [1].</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="845" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    [1]  I.ii.</t>
    <h>Humans are the main cause of global warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="846" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    first of all let me proof that global warming is happening .</t>
    <h>global warming is cause by humans</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="847" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Sunlight passes through the atmosphere.</t>
    <h>global warming is cause by humans</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="848" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> If this is so why is mars heating up as well? My opponent has proved that the earth is warming but has failed to prove that it is the humans fault.</t>
    <h>global warming is cause by humans</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="849" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    You never even proved that global warming is a real thing.(2) I use my source to prove that it is a hoax.</t>
    <h>global warming is cause by humans</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="850" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Developed countries are countries that tend to have the highest Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per capita, have well-developed basic physical and organizational structures needed for the operation of a society, or a infrastructure for transportation, communications, and energy.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="851" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is for this reason, that I support the resolution that Resolved: Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of Climate Change.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="852" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Due to my oppositions recent two forfeits I have began to come to the conclusion that they do not have any suitable counter-arguements for my contentions.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="853" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As I have stated; developed countries can fix climate change, they are responsible for climate change, and they MUST fix climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="854" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I extend my arguements.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="855" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote pro.</t>
    <h>Developed Countries should have a Moral Obligation to Mitigate the Effects of Climate Change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="856" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  Resolved: Devloped Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="857" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My thanks to my opponent for the debate, and I look forward to a fascinating dialogue.</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="858" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     C2: Firstly, this says 'developed countries' not 'USA'.</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="859" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Why should America care about what happens in Congo.</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="860" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent stated in his last speech that the United States is not included as a developed country.</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="861" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Unfortunately, it led me to a page I have taken a screenshot of and saved to my pictures[1].</t>
    <h>developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="862" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Developed countries is a term used to identify the wealthiest nations in the world, which include Western Europe, the United States, Canada, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand.</t>
    <h>Developed Coutries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="863" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My partner and I negate the resolution'Resolved: Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed Coutries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="864" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your first contention states that developed countries are largely responsible for climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed Coutries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="865" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    So my oppenents case is all about attacking me, he has not included any evidence to suppot his attacks, not only this but he also has failed to rebut his own case.</t>
    <h>Developed Coutries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="866" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Nothing left to say i suppose, Vote Aff as my oppenent hasnt showed up the last 2 rounds.</t>
    <h>Developed Coutries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="867" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Resolved: Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Developed Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="868" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now besides the fact that Pro has neglected to source or substantiate his claims, his point would still fall moot if the effects of global climate change will be worse than the effects of environmental regulations.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Developed Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="869" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First Round is acceptance.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Developed Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="870" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Extend refutation.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Developed Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="871" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept.</t>
    <h>Resolved: Developed Countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="872" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, the leading international body for the assessment of climate change, has stated that climate change has major environmental, social, political, and economic consequences.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="873" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> Reed Definitions: 'Developed countries: sovereign state which has a highly developed economy and advanced technological infrastructure relative to other less developed nations. </t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="874" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Since my opponent forfeited the previous round, extend my arguments.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="875" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote Pro.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="876" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Too few resourcesPro contends that there are too few resources, giving examples such as food and oil.</t>
    <h>The world is over populated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="877" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This currently large population is due to proper nutrition and modern medicine.</t>
    <h>The world is over populated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="878" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    For tonight's entertainment we have Luciano Pavarotti singing Stella.</t>
    <h>The world is over populated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="879" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ending this.</t>
    <h>The world is over populated</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="880" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Aff Resolved: Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="881" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Resolved: Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="882" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I extend all of my points and I would point out that my opponent can still post a case to be reviewed in the next round.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="883" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The first round is acceptance I as the Con side await a worthy aff challenger and wish good luck to both sides.</t>
    <h>Developed countries have a moral obligation to mitigate the effects of climate change.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="884" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Well, if Fox News said it, then it must be true.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="885" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Full Resolution:  Mankind is the main cause of global warming.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="886" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Rest of the Solar System  '...it was noted the planet [Mars] was experiencing rapid warming, similar to what the Earth is currently undergoing.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="887" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to thank Numidious for accepting this debate.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="888" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hello again, I appreciate my opponent's commitment also.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="889" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is a greenhouse gas, but it does not contribute to a change in the greenhouse effect, rather, it changes with the temperature of the atmosphere, and thus acts as a way of telling if we're doing things right.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="890" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Interesting points, Ron-Paul.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="891" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    CFCs Even though CFCs are mostly man-made in origin, there concentrations have been decreasing also: [3]Again, just like methane amounts, during the main warming times, CFCs concentration increases were decreasing, and are now negative.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="892" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am happy to accept this challenge and look forward to a very interesting debate - as I like to say, either you'll learn something or I will.</t>
    <h>Mankind Is the Main Cause of Global Warming</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="893" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global climate change according to me is manmade.</t>
    <h>Global Warming/cooling Are Cycles That "can" Be Influenced By Humans-not A Human Only Cause.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="894" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    What the historic record shows is that yes, climate change has been occurring since the planet's formation.</t>
    <h>Global Warming/cooling Are Cycles That "can" Be Influenced By Humans-not A Human Only Cause.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="895" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Sustainability in this debate refers to the ability for the trees to endure.</t>
    <h>Selective logging is not sustainable.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="896" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    When trees are cut down, plants such as vines, lianas, strangler figs and parasites which rely on the felled tree will have to go as well.</t>
    <h>Selective logging is not sustainable.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="897" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     'Sustainable development is development that meets the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs.' </t>
    <h>Selective logging is not sustainable.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="898" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It seems that I have to go through the rest of the rounds, then.</t>
    <h>Selective logging is not sustainable.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="899" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Vote Pro.</t>
    <h>Selective logging is not sustainable.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="900" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is here as a result of our misdeeds- like deforestation, burning of fossil fuels, emission of carbon dioxide and other harmful greenhouse gases.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle That Is Not Caused By Man.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="901" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is natural indeed, but we are speeding it up to a great extent.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="902" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes, we are definitely contributing to it.</t>
    <h>Is Global Climate Change Manmade?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="903" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It's a myth.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Problem</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="904" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We breath in O2 (Oxygen) when we breath out we make Co2, trees Breath that in and create more air.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not Only Caused By Loss Of Trees</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="905" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is not only caused by cutting trees, but  its one major reason of it.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not Only Caused By Loss Of Trees</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="906" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yeah i think so.</t>
    <h>Is Global Climate Change Manmade?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="907" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The answer is mostly yes.</t>
    <h>Is Global Climate Change Manmade?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="908" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global climate change according to me is manmade.</t>
    <h>Is Global Climate Change Manmade?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="909" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I stand for the statement wanted other people's opinions and debates on that.</t>
    <h>Is Global Climate Change Manmade?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="910" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    -Extreme droughts during prehistoric times and GREAT ICE AGES afterwards.</t>
    <h>Global Warming/cooling Are Cycles That "can" Be Influenced By Humans-not A Human Only Cause.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="911" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This house believes that developed countries have a higher obligation to combat climate change than developing countries.</t>
    <h>Climate Change. Developed Countries Vs Developing Countries</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="912" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I see that Pro has forfieted round 2.</t>
    <h>Climate Change. Developed Countries Vs Developing Countries</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="913" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will defeat you woolyman.</t>
    <h>Climate Change. Developed Countries Vs Developing Countries</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="914" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Global warming is a natural cycle and human kind has played only a small role in it, but that doesn't mean that we should stop protecting the environment.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Natural Cycle.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="915" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Resolution: The MAIN CAUSE of global warming is CO2 emissions made by humans  My opponent argues CO2 is the MAIN cause of global warming, I argue it is NOT the main cause.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="916" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I accept this debate and wish you the best of luck.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="917" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The greenhouse effect Before I refute the graph, I would like to note the graph STILL PROVES MY POINT.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="918" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    A greenhouse gas is a gas that traps heat in the atmosphere that prevents the head from escaping the earth.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="919" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Natural cycles:This argument is about solar cycles (as well as other cycles).</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="920" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    CO2 is like a sheet of plastic, it only absorbed 8% of the radiation.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="921" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    After looking at the evidence, I concede this debate.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="922" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    THE GREENHOUSE EFFECT  My partner's claim is that CO2 is very minute scale in the atmosphere and it really doesn't effect us that much.</t>
    <h>Global warming (full resolution in debate)</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="923" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First Round: Acceptance Second Round: Stating the case Third Round: Rebuttle Fourth Round: Rebuttle Fourth Round Concluding arguements.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="924" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The impact is that even if she proves that global warming is natural, and we refuse to accept my evidence that it is man-made, it doesn't matter because we have to then discuss the impacts of global warming in order to determine if it is an issue.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="925" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Response to Opponent's CaseThe first thing that she tells you is that she believes in global climate change.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="926" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I have no idea where she got this from; she did not source this statistic, so I cannot explain why the methodology of the statistic was wrong.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="927" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First, I will demonstrate that Global Warming does, in fact, exist even though it should not be happening.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="928" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This temperature increase is something that happens naturally, although it is also contributed to by human activity.' So as I've stated in the past.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="929" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First I would like to point out that I never said global warming was not happening.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="930" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My chart:  Yes I do recognize that my chart only goes back 4,000 years.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="931" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First, I would like to start off by saying that I do believe that there is a global climate change.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="932" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I assume that I will be discussing the negative impacts of Global Warming in this debate.</t>
    <h>Is Global Warming really an issue?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="933" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Wow u belive every thing fox says dont u i only watch the simpsons just wow are 5 or something.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="934" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hello what about the evidence.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="935" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Almost every study run by scientists to determine the validity of the threat of global warming is biased.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="936" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Maybe it is a lie, but a white lie.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="937" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Fox news said so.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is A Lie</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="938" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As my opponent has stated, it will be his burden to prove that there are other priorities other than the environment, and my burden will be to prove that environment should be the priority over these other issues.</t>
    <h>World Environment issues should be the priority</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="939" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The pro is arguing that the most important issue currently facing the world is related to its environment.</t>
    <h>World Environment issues should be the priority</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="940" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would like to make the rounds do the following: first round acceptance second round argument/and rebuttal in your case third round summary and why you should win.</t>
    <h>World Environment issues should be the priority</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="941" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It will be my burden to prove that there is at least one issue that should be a higher priority than the world's environment.</t>
    <h>World Environment issues should be the priority</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="942" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is a pretty clear vote for con.</t>
    <h>World Environment issues should be the priority</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="943" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Before I start I would to point out we are debating the energy source of nuclear power, not the weapons.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="944" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    An exception would be made for some scientific research, under very carefully controlled conditions.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="945" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Nuclear power:Power, especially electricity, the source of which is nuclear fission or fusion.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="946" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In 1985 at Oxford Union, in a debate so intense even the US president tuned in, he fought against Jerry Falwell, a noted friend of then-US-president Ronald Regan, arguing against the motion 'nuclear weapons are morally indefensible'.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="947" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank my opponent for a fun debate.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="948" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>  WasteLet's take a look at the total amount of byproducts produced by various forms of generating energy in the USA:Wind - nothingSolar - nothingTidal - nothingGeothermal - nothingHydroelectric - nothingNuclear - 12.3 million kilograms of toxic waste.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="949" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ~Refutation to the Pros case~It seems as though my opponent seems to worry about the nuclear power being weaponized, and its byproducts.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="950" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Nuclear is one of the most efficient power sources.</t>
    <h>Nuclear power should be banned</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="951" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    And the availability of drinkable water is decreasing for two reasons: 1 – Climate change is lessening our supply of water.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="952" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank my peer for yet another fine round,  'I would claim that an increase in water would mean an INCREASE in food supplies, since we would have more water to use on things like irrigation and watering of plants and crops.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="953" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yet is drinking water one of those that need be a problem.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="954" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This successfully refutes link, 'b) further causes the population to rise by increasing the quality of life.'  Moving on to Link part, 'a) it lowers our supply of water to give to other people.'</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="955" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I thank my opponent for a valiant effort to refute my position.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="956" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I make two independant points here: an increase in global population (Kates 1) and a decrease in the availability in water we can drink (Arlington Insitute 1/2).</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="957" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    For shooting himself not only in the foot, but in the head with the vast amount of concessions he made in his last round.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="958" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Best of luck Zaradi :)  Resolved: Access to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="959" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro refutes and defends.3.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="960" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Ill start out this round by thanking my peer for such a fine debate as I have thoroughly enjoyed myself.</t>
    <h>Acess to drinking water ought to be valued as a human right instead of a commodity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="961" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now, as I pointed out before in my previous argument, an argument you dropped I might add, sometimes flights are needed for immediate travel and this demand will never go away.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="962" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'Changing something in favor o something that isn't wildly accepted is ridiculous.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="963" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Also; airline travel is the safest form of travel [5] and forcing people out of the planes and into cars will increase the risk of accident and injury due to car crashes.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="964" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The emmission contains extremely harmful gases which damage our ozone layer.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="965" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My empirical evidence and my numbers coupled with the outstanding reason I presented have caused my opponent to forfeit.Extend All arguments.Vote Con.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="966" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First round is acceptance, all stats and facts must be sourced.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="967" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Make your case.</t>
    <h>Airline flights should be taxed much higher than they already are</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="968" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Expensive to build  Absorbs impact of the waves Over time the wall will erode Visually unattractive.  Protects the land close to the ocean Costly to maintain Can be expensive to obtain and transport.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="969" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    1st round is for acceptance And by accepting this debate you will be on the pro side on the building of sea walls along the coast.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="970" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This looks like an interesting debate :) I look forward to your arguments in Round 2.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="971" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Look at this image: As you can see, there was a lot of destruction caused, which could have been reduced by sea walls.' 'we' need them because some people want to invest in a expensive house that will ineffably be destroyed by the waves.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="972" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    [b]'Sea walls do protect against small tidal waves'[/b] Right I do understand that, but may I ask why do we need them.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="973" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Even though hillside forestation isn't permanent, it is still done because it is an effective way to stop avalanches, in the way that sea walls are effective at reducing the impact of tidal waves and tsunamis.</t>
    <h>Sea Walls</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="974" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    She does what she wants.</t>
    <h>Global Warming - Disaster For The World</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="975" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    But we can't do much as of now.</t>
    <h>Global Warming - Disaster For The World</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="976" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I think v must do our bit to save d world n so 2gether d whole world does someting and w can save d earth.</t>
    <h>Global Warming - Disaster For The World</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="977" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Im new and hope to enjoy being a part of this site.</t>
    <h>Global Warming - Disaster For The World</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="978" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I believe that this He3 material would not be worth a colonization because if it simply slows cancer all your doing is buying them time for their unstoppable death so why would people buy it to make their lives a bit longer.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="979" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    moon has He3 which is rare on Earth.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="980" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I believe that colonization of the moon would be useless to humanity and major waste of resources.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="981" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t> I don't think the moon a rock flouting around in space is worth the hundreds maybe even thousands of human lives lost in the process of taking it. </t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="982" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Yes the moon may have earthly resources but it dose not have trees nor farmland and once again we have no idea what amount of the resources the moon has it may not be a lot.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="983" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    it's to late in the game so I guess I'll use a plan text THe U.S.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="984" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    He3 can be used to help to detect the smuggling of nuclear wepons.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="985" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro drops India arguement and doesn't refute the U.S.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="986" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>   Because the Chinese are two seconds faster than us dose not make them a threat also global warming.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="987" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pro agrees 2.</t>
    <h>colonization of the moon would fail and not be worth it to humanity</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="988" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Man does not control nature.</t>
    <h>We ALL Should Do Something About Global Warming. Because It's Creating An Ice-Age As Well.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="989" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Star of the Day, here we come.</t>
    <h>We Should All Care About Global Warming!</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="990" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I do believe that Global Warming is a problem in today's society.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="991" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     There are too many good minds with good data who are not afraid to raise serious questions and doubt, especially the part regarding man's contribution to warming, if indeed, there is a significant overall trend.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="992" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Current research suggests that coastal stations in Greenland are experiencing a cooling trend, and average summer air temperatures at the summit of the Greenland Ice Sheet have decreased at the rate of 4°F per decade since measurements began in 1987.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="993" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The glaciers are melting, causing the decrease of polar bears, the oceans are rising causing floods and buildings under the sea.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="994" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Watch how fast the glaciers are melting.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="995" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The fear of a loss in our atmospheric protection from the sun's harmful rays, the widespread death of plants, and the eventual death of humans.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not As Urgent As It Is Believed To Be.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="996" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is proof that there is a slight increase in the adverage temperature around the world, but not near the extent that wackos such as Al Gore would like to claim.</t>
    <h>"Global Warming" Is Largely Exaggerated.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="997" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If all the greenhouse gases that are being emitted everyday into the sky was not important, then so why would so many scientists even talk about it, huh.</t>
    <h>"Global Warming" Is Largely Exaggerated.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="998" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    By experimentation, we can tell that carbon dioxide,carbon monoxide and other greenhouse gases has a higher specific heat capacity than air itself.</t>
    <h>"Global Warming" Is Largely Exaggerated.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="999" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I believe that climate change does exist, as it has for the entire history of Earth, but think global warming isn't as caused by humans as people think it is.</t>
    <h>"Global Warming" Is Largely Exaggerated.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="1000" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Today, The Earth is too old like an old ppl, it may be have its disease.</t>
    <h>Global Warming Is Not Caused By Human Activity</h>
  </pair>
</entailment-corpus>
