<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entailment-corpus lang="EN">
  <pair id="1" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That way by definition climate change isn't really going to exist until the distant future when our sun finally cr@ps out.
</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="2" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    That's why we need to launch an immediate campaign to paint ball all the arctic animals with colors that will help them camouflage to their newly colored surroundings.
</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="3" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This further may endanger the lives of the animals in areas around the North and South Poles.
</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="4" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is usually accepted that climate change happens and affects oceans and Earth as an ecosystem.
</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="5" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Free speech is ALL speech!
</t>
    <h>Climate Skeptics Should All Be Arrested</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="6" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This would cause the oceans to become abnormally basic and this has only happened once in the last 25 million years: Ocean pH 25 million years: https://www.manicore.com... (I know it shows acidification at the end but this does not contradict my argument because it is a different result of more Co2.)  Fact 6: Almost every single computer model made by the IPCC is wrong.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="7" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent then says, 'if you are so sure you are correct and there are so many climate change deniers, why don't you publish your r2-3 arguments in a peer reviewed journal?' My response to this is that: 1.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="8" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Summer 2003 was the hottest in Europe since 1500, very likely due in part to anthropogenic climate change.''
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="9" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Therefore it is an automatic win for the Con as my opponent can decide when they want to break the rules or not, leaving me at an unfair disadvantage.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="10" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Unable to find any peer reviewed articles my opponent relies upon non-credible sources.I ask this, if you are so sure you are correct and there are so many climate change deniers, why don't you publish your r2-3 arguments in a peer reviewed journal?
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="11" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'The World Health Organisation estimates that the warming and precipitation trends due to anthropogenic climate change of the past 30 years already claim over 150,000 lives annually.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="12" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    R1 Acceptance R2-3 Arguments amp; rebuttals R4 No new arguments  You beat me last time, I figured its time to challenge you to a rematch.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="13" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I gladly accept your debate and look forward to your arguments.
</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="14" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Trump has threatened to pull the US out of the agreement.' [0]'Trump: ‘I’m not a big believer in man-made climate change.’' [1]' Any and all weather events are used by the GLOBAL WARMING HOAXSTERS to justify higher taxes to save our planet!
</t>
    <h>Donald Trump is a climate change denier.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="15" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    As a devout socialist (coughs and splutters- apparently the word communist is illegal nowadays) I can confirm that the idea of an environment is a plot to destroy the capitalist infidels of the west, the idea is to push their focus so far into ideas of global warming and the environment that they will not see the coming revolution.
</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="16" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now Karl Marx and Darwin had contact, again I can't show impossible, but can show improbable.
</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="17" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I'm not sure where some people get these ideas from, but I think this is so crazy I can't even see the other point of view.
</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="18" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Therefore, the Paris attacks were caused in part by global climate change.[6] I have fufilled my burden of proof that there is a 99% chance that climate change is a threat.VI. Man madeNow the most difficult part, to prove the changes are man-made.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and is a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="19" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If we start jailing whistle blowers we could be in a lot of trouble. [4] Remember that 97% of climate change scientists agree.
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="20" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is an overwhelming scientific consensus climate change presents a serious risk to the future of the Earth and to mankind.
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="21" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ' stupidape  Jailing the climate change deniers could backfire.
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="22" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Nevertheless some people think we should jail climate change deniers. [0]
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="23" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We could also find out years from now that children aren't harmed in the production of child porn even though the evidence right now is substantial and overwhelming children are being harmed by child porn.
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="24" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We can't in good conscience risk the lives of potentially hundreds of millions of people because of an extremely remote chance the scientific consensus is wrong.
</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="25" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    To conclude my argument, I will provide a graph of Co2 and Temperature over the long term that should, on its own, disprove entirely the idea of man-made climate change. http://www.paulmacrae.com...
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="26" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    ' The introduction of the International Agreement on the Conservation of Polar Bears in 1973, which restricted or even banned hunting in some circumstances, consequently resulted in an increase in polar bear numbers.' [6]As you can see, I've destroyed all your arguments while proving causation of CO2 to increase temperature.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="27" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Manmade global climate change is the general increase in temperature at rapid rates that is mainly caused by CO2 from industry increases.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="28" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your first argument, 'Carbon dioxide is at 404.48 parts per million and the temperature has increased 1.4 degrees Fahrenheit since 1880.' That is not a scientific argument.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="29" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We have already discussed this topic and my opponent brought up a good argument against it but I disproved it in my last argument (and the comment section). (Keep in mind that in the last 20 years 25% of all Co2 released by man has been released during that period)  Fact 4: The Earth has been warming for the last 20,000 years and the recent uptick started in the 1700's, before the industrial revolution. https://conscioustourism.files.wordpress.com...
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="30" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Rather than trying to prove me wrong my opponent's aim is to make the problem more complex and cast doubt.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="31" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Man Made Climate Change, The FACTS:  1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the world's climate: Many people I have met say, 'Manmade global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!' but how do you actually test that.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="32" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In conclusion, not only have you ignored the majority of my first argument, you state claims that I am not even trying to disprove.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="33" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The Great Global Warming Swindle Full Movie ( I know this is long but if you have the time then watch at least some of it)  2. Climate Change in 12 minutes - the skeptics case  These two sources are really great and show a lot of flaws in your side of the argument  Sadly, I only saw them yesterday so I couldn't use their points in this debate :)  Thank you for debating and I hope you look into both sides because there are legitimate reasons why people don't believe in man made global warming.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="34" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    'has reached 400 parts per million (ppm) for the first time in recorded history, according to data from the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii.' [3]Impact, there is a clear and strong positive correlation between CO2 and tempature.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="35" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Pope Francis recognizes climate change and calls for swift action. [0]Impact: I think the Pope knows what he is doing and thus man-made global climate change is real and a threat.The scientific angle, inconvenient truth [1].
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="36" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Maybe, just maybe if I had a year to respond I could defeat you.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="37" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Here are my reasons: 1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the world's climate: Many people I have met say, 'Man made global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!' but how do you actually test that.
</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="38" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Other sources say that the correlation strength is just .07 or.02 (1998-2007). according to Joe Bastardi, Co2 has a correlation strength to temperature of just .43 (1895-2007).
</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="39" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My evidence that CO2 has a huge impact is here:  1: My opponent has acknowledged that CO2 is a green house gas.
</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="40" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    So even if you believe my opponent that it is actually the water vapor that is the more disastrous greenhouse gas, this problem stems from CO2 also, which stems from humans. http://www.nasa.gov...  Basically my opponent is stating we would need more CO2 to see an impact which is not a scientific claim and there is an undoubted correlation between CO2 and warming.
</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="41" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thus I hold my claim that humans are impacting climate change.'  To respond to this, I would like to bring up the argument that there is not that much Co2 in the atmosphere compared to the Earths past.
</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="42" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    If I said something was going to happen and here's what we expect to see to show it is happening, but then none of my predictions came true, you might assume my overall premise/hypothesis is also incorrect.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="43" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In summary, species including humans will struggle to adapt to such changes, if adaptation to such a change is even possible. [3]Impact, high rate of temperature change equals mass extinctions, which are a threat.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="44" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Everything portraying us destroying the world centers years earlier without adequate research and a documentary (cited by my opponent) where it's shown to have inaccuracies and flat out lies to get the agenda across.' JcMagic2015 Climate change is complicated.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="45" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I've found a nice article showing that it's a much deeper issue than what you have alluded to and there is plenty of evidence that, while we are increasing CO2 in the atmosphere, you're idea of threat does not have enough to stand on.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="46" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    However, where I disagree is the threat.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="47" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Now I will Strengthen my original cases1: Fossil Fuels do not cause an increase in CO2 emissions, which makes the first part of the IPCC's basic version of global warming invalidMy opponent has conceded this point (see above for more details)2: Despite common belief the last few years have not been the warmest on recordI have shown my opponent's rebuttal of this claim to be false, and his claim of a logical fallacy to be false, however I'd like to strengthen this point more.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="48" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The conclusion from the analysis of the data is that while there has been a.05 degree warming trend since 2002, according to researchers that is 'statistically insignificant' [2] The small upward trend from 1978 to 2015 is .2 degrees Celsius and is once again classifiable as statistically insignificant and is not proof of any man made global warming, in fact the lack of a significant upward trend shows not only that global warming predictions on climate and temperatures have been well off, but that there may not be any man made global warming at all. (excuse the site on the chart, woodfortrees.org is not where I got the chart, the source I used for the chart is the one listed as source 2)3: Antarctic Ice was larger than ever in 2012 and 2014, thus the Antarctic Ice caps have not been melting which is thought to be a sideffect of the Global Warming theoryNASA satillites discovered that the antarctic sea ice had reached a new record high in 2012 and then again in 2014, in 2014 it set a record for the largest Antarctic Sea Ice in recorded history [3].
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="49" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent calls this point 'cherry picking' however as I have proven, this is not true, and because my opponent has not offered contrary evidence and because of that this point still stands3: Antarctic Ice was larger than ever in 2012 and 2014, thus the Antarctic Ice caps have not been melting which is thought to be a sideffect of the Global Warming theoryMy opponent's first reputation was to say that the ice caps would not melt if Global Warming occurred, however I have shown that this is false, then my opponent made a refutation that is not in contradiction to anything that I stated, so this point still stands.4: There is no direct link between CO2 Emissions and Temperature IncreasesMy opponent has neglected to mention either of my graphs and my opponent's evidence has been refuted making this point still relevant in this debate.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="50" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thus, an increase in ice mass.'As you can see your Antarctica ice argument provides supporting evidence global climate change is happening. [5]4: There is no direct link between CO2 Emissions and Temperature IncreasesThis is stage 3c of climate change denial. [3]''When viewed coarsely, historical CO2 levels and temperature show a tight correlation.
</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
</entailment-corpus>
