<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entailment-corpus lang="EN">
  <pair id="1" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Climate change would affect absolutely everywhere on earth.  Eventually.    That's why we should define normal climate as + or - 100 degrees daily average.  That way by definition climate change isn't really going to exist until the distant future when our sun finally cr@ps out.</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="2" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Of course it is.  All that white fur will make them sitting ducks if the snow and ice melt away.  That's why we need to launch an immediate campaign to paint ball all the arctic animals with colors that will help them camouflage to their newly colored surroundings.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="3" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is usually accepted that climate change happens and affects oceans and Earth as an ecosystem. This further may endanger the lives of the animals in areas around the North and South Poles.</t>
    <h>Is Climate Change A Danger For Arctic And Antarctic Animals?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="4" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    It is usually accepted that climate change happens and affects oceans and Earth as an ecosystem. This further may influence the economy in various countries and ultimately the lives of the people living there.</t>
    <h>Does Climate Change Affect The Economy Of My Country?</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="5" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Free speech is ALL speech.</t>
    <h>Climate Skeptics Should All Be Arrested</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="6" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     Fact 1: There has been no significant atmospheric warming since 1998. No warming 1: http://blogs.news.com.au. No warming 2: http://4.bp.blogspot.com. (Specifically on pg 6 but I suggest you read more)  Fact 2: Co2 is an extraordinarily weak greenhouse gas.  Fact 9: All major planet bodies in our solar system are experiencing rapid climate change, indicating that the heating on Earth could be caused by something in the solar system, not the planet.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="7" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First my opponent says that I should have asked questions about the structure earlier in the debate but ignores the fact that, in the comment section, I did ask about the order of the debate and explain what I thought it meant. Therefore, I did alert my opponent to my confusion and my opponent either chose to ignore it or did not see it but either way I made my confusion known.  My opponent then says, quot;if you are so sure you are correct and there are so many climate change deniers, why donapos;t you publish your r2-3 arguments in a peer reviewed journal?quot; My response to this is that: 1. This is because people choose not to be skeptical because believing in man made global warming is how you get grants. I donapos;t publish my findings in a peer reviewed journal because they would not get published.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="8" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent throws around a bunch of irrelevant facts to try to disprove highly credible and peer reviewed articles. I added a few more peer reviewed articles to back up my points. I use peer reviewed to prove that anthropic climate change is real and a threat. The below quote, although lengthy explains that man-made climate change isnapos;t something far in the future, its an event that has occurred already and is continuing to occur and claim human lives. http://dx.doi.org...5.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="9" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent breaks their own rules by not rebutting my argument.  Rebuttals: Strong hurricane numbers have stayed almost constant since 1880: http://commdiginews.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com.  Sea levels are not rising due to heat because the Argo Buoy System data shows that the ocean has not warmed since we started measuring (2003) This shows that the sea only seems to be rising because of tectonic plate movement and the supposed rise is only due to a natural cycle: https://logiclogiclogic.files.wordpress.com. This has been blamed on increased precipitation causing more snowfall but if this is true then how come the same thing isnapos;t happening in the Arctic.  It is true that heat wave frequency has increased but other natural disaster frequencies have stayed constant proving that the climate change threat is either nonexistent or being exaggerated.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="10" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    quot;R2-3 Arguments amp; rebuttalsquot; StupidapeI didnapos;t break my own rules. This means you can perform any combination of arguments and rebuttals in r2 as well as r3. If you had any questions about the structure the best time would have been before accepting the debate and/or round 1. My opponent uses the tired strategy of cherry picking evidence and red herrings by climate change deniers. Unable to find any peer reviewed articles my opponent relies upon non-credible sources.I ask this, if you are so sure you are correct and there are so many climate change deniers, why donapos;t you publish your r2-3 arguments in a peer reviewed journal.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="11" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My first source shows beyond a resonable doubt man-made climate change exists. [1][2] I know my argument is short, but when you got peer reviewed articles as source stating your claim, there is no reason to make a longer argument. quot;The World Health Organisation estimates that the warming and precipitation trends due to anthropogenic climate change of the past 30 years already claim over 150,000 lives annually. http://iopscience.iop.org...1. http://www.nature.com...2.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="12" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    R1 Acceptance R2-3 Arguments amp; rebuttals R4 No new arguments  You beat me last time, I figured its time to challenge you to a rematch.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="13" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I gladly accept your debate and look forward to your arguments. Good luck.</t>
    <h>Anthropic climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="14" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    quot;Trump, who backed climate action in 2009 but now describes climate change as “%^amp;”, is also out of step with the US and other governments’ efforts to turn emissions-cutting pledges into concrete actions in the wake of the Paris climate agreement. Trump has threatened to pull the US out of the agreement.quot; [0]quot;Trump: ‘I’m not a big believer in man-made climate change.’quot; [1]quot; Any and all weather events are used by the GLOBAL WARMING HOAXSTERS to justify higher taxes to save our planet. — Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) January 26, 2014 NBC News just called it the great freeze - coldest weather in years. https://www.theguardian.com...1.</t>
    <h>Donald Trump is a climate change denier.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="15" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Hello, loyal comrades.  As a devout socialist (coughs and splutters- apparently the word communist is illegal nowadays) I can confirm that the idea of an environment is a plot to destroy the capitalist infidels of the west, the idea is to push their focus so far into ideas of global warming and the environment that they will not see the coming revolution. Before they know it, the means of production will have been seized and the bourgeoise crippled.  The master plan for the environmental decoy was first formed by loyal soviet Leonid Kzyladskystok, whoapos;s idea was taken by Comrade Stalin, and itapos;s creator purged.  In more depth, the plot is to pull the focus of weak, populist politicians such as Barack Obama to the issues of global warming, and how to prevent it, while secretly building up a force to crush the bourgeoise and initiate the revolution.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="16" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I would say the idea of the environment started with Charles Darwin in 1859. quot;The theory of evolution by natural selection, first formulated in Darwinapos;s book quot;On the Origin of Speciesquot; in 1859, is the process by which organisms change over time as a result of changes in heritable physical or behavioral traits. quot; [1]quot;In 1848, Marx and fellow German thinker Friedrich Engels published “The Communist Manifesto,” which introduced their concept of socialism as a natural result of the conflicts inherent in the capitalist system.quot; [2]As you can see the idea of the environment came out after the idea of Karl Marx in 1848. If the idea of the environment came before Marx was born I could show this as impossible. http://www.livescience.com...2.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="17" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Iapos;m not sure where some people get these ideas from, but I think this is so crazy I canapos;t even see the other point of view.  Burden of proof will be 51% on Pro and 49% on me. Since I canapos;t even see the other point of view, Iapos;ll let Pro go first.  http://www.huffingtonpost.com.</t>
    <h>The concept of the environment is a socialist plot to destroy capitalism.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="18" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Man made VII. [0] It is well known that carbon is increasing in parts per million. Co2 and global temperature have a two way causality relationship. Meaning as the oceans heat, Co2 is released which in turns heats up the ocean more. Therefore, it is safe to say that Co2 causes global climate change.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and is a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="19" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    The problem with your argument is humans have been wrong with a lot of ideas. [2] Just because the majority of scientists think man made climate change is real and a threat, does not mean the scientists are correct. quot; quot;Does the Earth go around the Sun, or does the Sun go around the Earth?quot;If you answered the latter, youapos;re among a quarter of Americans who also got it wrong, according to a new report by the National Science Foundation. quot; [3]There is a chance that the entire global warming/climate change is a scam. That the deniers are whistle blowers.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="20" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is an overwhelming scientific consensus climate change presents a serious risk to the future of the Earth and to mankind. Many of the threats we face due to climate change are insidious and while with others the connection may not be noticed by the deniers. Among these are the spread of potentially lethal diseases such as that caused by the Zika virus.  There are a limited number of circumstances under which free speech can be restricted. One of them is child pornography.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="21" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I reassert my strongest argument in r2. Assume for a second that the deniers are wrong. Jailing the deniers could backfire. Causing them to become martyrs per say. Holding back political change and giving the deniers a louder voice.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="22" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Iapos;m against jailing Climate change deniers. I also think it sets a bad precedence. I would hate to see a 15 year old teenager go to jail for running off at the mouth.  Nevertheless some people think we should jail climate change deniers. http://www.washingtontimes.com.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="23" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We could also find out years from now that children arenapos;t harmed in the production of child porn even though the evidence right now is substantial and overwhelming children are being harmed by child porn. Even though that remote possibility exists it does not mean we shouldnapos;t jail child pornographers.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="24" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    We canapos;t in good conscience risk the lives of potentially hundreds of millions of people because of an extremely remote chance the scientific consensus is wrong. You want both sides to be able to debate-- but there is nothing really to debate.</t>
    <h>Jail climate change deniers.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="25" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent accepts that his first argument is a correlation so there is no need to strengthen my argument there.  My opponents second argument states, quot;quot;quot;When the Earth comes out of an ice age, the warming is not initiated by CO2 but by changes in the Earthapos;s orbit. So CO2 causes warming AND rising temperature causes CO2 rise.  Line 2: This line is just wrong. For an example, look at this graph: http://www.geocraft.com.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="26" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Second, I would like to note my opponentapos;s response is very dense. quot;Your first argument, quot;Carbon dioxide is at 404.48 parts per million and the temperature has increased 1.4 degrees Fahrenheit since 1880.quot; That is not a scientific argument. There is no REAL evidence to suggest that Co2 impact temperature.quot; rammer5678Yes, you are correct as presented it is a correlation. quot;quot;When the Earth comes out of an ice age, the warming is not initiated by CO2 but by changes in the Earthapos;s orbit. He also predicted the polar bears would all have died out by now.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="27" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    There is so much information on the topic that rather than reiterate all of it I will make a short summary. Also burden of proof will be 51% on my opponent and 49% on me. Manmade global climate change is the general increase in temperature at rapid rates that is mainly caused by CO2 from industry increases. Carbon dioxide is at 404.48 parts per million and the temperature has increased 1.4 degrees Fahrenheit since 1880. Al Goreapos;s inconvenient truth is still a master piece, and I will not accept defeat until my opponent can defeat the documentary.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="28" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your first argument, quot;Carbon dioxide is at 404.48 parts per million and the temperature has increased 1.4 degrees Fahrenheit since 1880.quot; That is not a scientific argument. There is no REAL evidence to suggest that Co2 impact temperature. Especially when 25% of all Co2 produced by man has been released in the last 20 years and in that time there has been NO NET WARMING.  You also make it sound like 1.4 degrees is what was predicted by the models showing Co2 causing temperature. https://wattsupwiththat.files.wordpress.com.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="29" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent does not counter-argue even one of the points I made in my previous arguments/in the comment section. If he had simply read the counter arguments I provided, you can see clearly that I do not try to distract from the topic at hand.  Seeing as my opponent made no further arguments and did not make any comments about how I disproved all of his (relating to man causing the warming) claims, I am only left with the option to strengthen my own argument.  Fact 1: Co2 is a weak greenhouse gas. This disproves man-made climate change because the water vapor doesnquot;t cause the earth to warm more than the clouds it forms causes the Earth to cool.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="30" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponentapos;s argument seems endless and confusing. Rather than trying to prove me wrong my opponentapos;s aim is to make the problem more complex and cast doubt. I make only a few arguments and my opponent makes at least 4 arguments for each argument I make. Making the debate grow in size and complexity until nobody can tell who won.  https://thinkprogress.org.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="31" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I am here to debate the MAN MADE side of climate change. I do not disagree that the world is warming, I only believe the current warming trends are exaggerated and people are freaking out over a natural process.  Man Made Climate Change, The FACTS:  1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the worldquot;s climate: Many people I have met say, quot;Manmade global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!quot; but how do you actually test that. Why is Co2 more important than all of these factors. This shows that the idea that Co2 causes warming is less science then it is religion because you are putting your faith in a computer model rather than observing and recording data.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="32" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>     You firstly say that, quot;The temperature has increased .87 Celsius.quot; This is true, but you forgot to mention that the warming period that caused this rise started in the 1700apos;s before the industrial revolution. In addition to this, the world has been naturally warming for the last 20,000 years.  https://conscioustourism.files.wordpress.com.  According to your second argument, Co2 is at 400 ppm. Co2 has been over 10000 ppm in the past and temperature had been relatively low at that time.quot;  There may be a clear and strong positive correlation between Co2 and temperature but this correlation has been weak compared to that of sun spots.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="33" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for being honest and admitting you donapos;t understand my arguments. I strongly encourage you to do your own research into both sides of the argument. That is what I did and ultimately found that the con side has a better argument.  Two things that could help you get started in your research into the con side are these YouTube videos: 1. The Great Global Warming Swindle Full Movie ( I know this is long but if you have the time then watch at least some of it)  2.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="34" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Your arguments are long and with little breaks between paragraphs. quot;Not only is the idea that Co2 is causing the recent warming preposterous, but it just doesnquot;t make any sense. quot; epidexipteryxThe temperature has increased .87 Celsius. quot;has reached 400 parts per million (ppm) for the first time in recorded history, according to data from the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii.quot; [3]Impact, there is a clear and strong positive correlation between CO2 and tempature. http://climate.nasa.gov...3.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="35" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Iapos;m putting this under religion since people are talking faith based approaches to climate change.I have noticed that a surprising number of people still think global climate change is a hoax. Pope Francis recognizes climate change and calls for swift action. [0]Impact: I think the Pope knows what he is doing and thus man-made global climate change is real and a threat.The scientific angle, inconvenient truth [1]. Impact, scientific evidence clearly backs up this claim in the documentary an inconvenient truth. http://www.nytimes.com...1.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="36" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Iapos;m just going to give up at this point. I canapos;t even understand most of what your stating let alone formulate a response. Iapos;ve had other debates on this site that even after months of reviewing my opponentapos;s argument I still couldnapos;t make heads out of tails out of my opponentapos;s arguments. Maybe, just maybe if I had a year to respond I could defeat you.  Thanks for the debate.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="37" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Please stick to only the man-made part of this argument. Science is based off of hard facts and evidence to support claims, not a consensus of random scientists whether they studied climate or not.  Here are my reasons: 1.There is NO way to test whether Co2 is the most contributing factor to the worldquot;s climate: Many people I have met say, quot;Man made global warming is real and Co2 is the cause!quot; but how do you actually test that. Why is Co2 more important than all of these factors. This shows that the idea that Co2 causes warming is less science then it is religion because you are putting your faith in a computer model rather than observing and recording data.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="38" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    *Sorry for assuming your gender but I didnapos;t realize that I wrote quot;hequot; instead of quot;theyquot; until the very end. :)  Im going to start my argument by countering my opponents observations. There is not doubt in my mind that Co2 causes warming. To clarify, I believe the warming Co2 creates is insignificant and barely has an effect on climate. He is correct in saying that a consensus is more scientific then a home experiment but a scientific paper or research article is better then both.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="39" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent kept mentioning that I was making claims without backing them. I was unclear but thatapos;s because my case was at the bottom and had gone over that evidence. To eliminate as much confusion as possible I will add all that evidence with those statements that appeared to have none.  My evidence that CO2 has a huge impact is here:  1: My opponent has acknowledged that CO2 is a green house gas.  3: If CO2 causes warming, and humans are omitting extra CO2 that we are having an impact on climate.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="40" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    First I would like to thank my opponent for the opportunity for this debate,  I would like to start by making a few observations: 1) I am arguing that the human race has had a measurable impact on global warming. I acknowledge that natural climate change does happen. I will debate that humans are contributing to recent global warming. However, it has to be seen that a scientific study by real scientists is going to be more reliable than some kind of theory or home conducted experiment.  My opponents 1st point states that there is no hard proof that CO2 from humans is the most important part to causing global warming.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="41" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponents first second and third points state, quot;My opponent has acknowledged that CO2 is a green house gas. Green house gasses cause global warming. humans are netting 15 gigatons of carbon into the atmosphere that has no place in the carbon cycle. If CO2 causes warming, and humans are omitting extra CO2 that we are having an impact on climate. Thus I hold my claim that humans are impacting climate change.quot;  To respond to this, I would like to bring up the argument that there is not that much Co2 in the atmosphere compared to the Earths past.</t>
    <h>Man Made Climate Change Is Fake</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="42" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I like how you reference a democrat to put doubt into my quot;conservativequot; site. This is a scientific issue, not a political one.  Supporting evidence that the claims of manmade global climate change are dramatically overstated: Weapos;ve seen record total amounts of ice, snow, and cold. Iapos;ve shown multiple times that the predictions of those claiming manmade climate change is going to destroy the world have been incorrect. We are warming the client.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="43" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent is correct the Earthapos;s temperature has been hotter a long time ago. This falls into the stage 4a of climate change denial. [2] Meaning my opponent accepts the first part of the resolution but rejects the second half.The problem is not the temperature itself, but the rate of change. Next my opponent uses information sourced from an ultra conservative website called the dailycaller.com I will first attack the source of the argument and then the argument itself. http://grist.org...3.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="44" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    quot;I like how you reference a democrat to put doubt into my quot;conservativequot; site. Global climate change is one of the dividing lines between liberals and conservatives. quot;Nature still produces FAR more CO2 than man. Everything portraying us destroying the world centers years earlier without adequate research and a documentary (cited by my opponent) where itapos;s shown to have inaccuracies and flat out lies to get the agenda across.quot; JcMagic2015 Climate change is complicated. https://images.duckduckgo.com...s://images.duckduckgo.com...; alt=quot;Climate hits 400ppm of CO2 for first time in 3 million years ...quot; /gt;Tempature graph.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="45" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    This is a much deeper topic and, iapos;ll say again, this is a scientific debates. Just because politicians have used it to pick sides, doesnapos;t mean it has to be political.  I donapos;t feel youapos;ve sufficiently countered my points and Iapos;ll go a step further. Iapos;ve found a nice article showing that itapos;s a much deeper issue than what you have alluded to and there is plenty of evidence that, while we are increasing CO2 in the atmosphere, youapos;re idea of threat does not have enough to stand on.  http://www.americantraditions.org...(CO2)%20Does%20Not%20Cause%20Global%20Warming.htm.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="46" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    I will agree that humans have had a measurable (not stating how measurable) effect on the Earth. However, where I disagree is the threat. The Earth has been SIGNFICANTLY hotter in the past (and more dynamic for that matter), see http://www.wrsc.org.  Do I think being quot;more greenquot; is helpful, sure. Rather than an inconvenient truth, an inaccurate partial-truth.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="47" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    In this round I will be refuting my opponentapos;s arguments and I will be resupporting my own arguments My opponent statedquot;First my arguments still stand. I think everyone already knows the Pope is not a climate change scientist.quot;But what my opponent fails to realize is that quoting the pope is not an argument, an argument needs evidence, the quote from the Pope is not evidence of climate change, rather it is only a claim followed by my opponentapos;s warrant. The Popeapos;s statement does not further your case (unless he was a climate scientist, then it would)So, because the pope is not a climate researcher I really donapos;t even need to refute his statement but I have done so by showing that the Pope is not a climate scientist. In his first rebuttal my opponent stated thatquot;science has shown repeatably that CO2 emissions increase green house gasesquot;, but he shows no specific evidence of this occurring. In fact, if I had cherry picked this evidence it would not show the .2 degree warming trend that it did...What is even more ironic is that my opponent goes on to say quot;El Nino was responsible for the height of the graph.quot; But even I conceded that the warming trend was there, in fact my opponent just contradicted his entire case by calling the warming trend that was apparent on the graph; El Nino, a regional, natural phenomena, that has nothing to do with Global Climate Change.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="48" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Thank you for posting this debate, I hope to be a worthy opponent!!!!Your argument is based on the popeapos;s opinion as well as a scientific documentaryMy argument will be based on historical evidence as well as current scientific evidence that contradicts the theory of Global Climate ChangeFirst Iapos;d like to clarify that Global Warming and Global Climate Change are the same theory with a different name and I will treat them as such. First, Iapos;d like to define Global Climate Change (or Warming)Thus the theory of Global Climate Change (warming) is - a change in global climate patterns, in particular a change apparent from the mid to late 20th century onward and attributed to the increased levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide produced by the use of fossil fuels.Iapos;d like to give a more simplified version of the above statement by giving this general statement released by the IPCC on what Climate Change is quot;Increasing fossil fuel causes increasing carbon dioxide in the air; and increasing carbon dioxide in the air causes climate change.quot;Next, Iapos;d like to refute my opponentapos;s argumentsArgument 1) Pope Francis recognizes climate change and he quot;Knows what he is doing and thus man-made global climate change is real and a threatquot; My Response: Pope Francis has no college degree in science (he does have a quot;tituloquot; as a chemical technician, which is not a college degree) and either way he is not a climatologist and his opinion does not count as an expertapos;s opinion and his opinion is on par with the opinion of world leaders and celebrities. Argument 2) An Inconvenient Truth My Response: I will watch the entirety of this movie so I can refute the movie in my next argumentNow I will give my basic arguments1: Fossil Fuels do not cause an increase in CO2 emissions, which makes the first part of the IPCCapos;s basic version of global warming invalidDuring World War II, U.S. The conclusion from the analysis of the data is that while there has been a .05 degree warming trend since 2002, according to researchers that is quot;statistically insignificantquot; [2] The small upward trend from 1978 to 2015 is .2 degrees Celsius and is once again classifiable as statistically insignificant and is not proof of any man made global warming, in fact the lack of a significant upward trend shows not only that global warming predictions on climate and temperatures have been well off, but that there may not be any man made global warming at all. (excuse the site on the chart, woodfortrees.org is not where I got the chart, the source I used for the chart is the one listed as source 2)3: Antarctic Ice was larger than ever in 2012 and 2014, thus the Antarctic Ice caps have not been melting which is thought to be a sideffect of the Global Warming theoryNASA satillites discovered that the antarctic sea ice had reached a new record high in 2012 and then again in 2014, in 2014 it set a record for the largest Antarctic Sea Ice in recorded history [3].</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="49" entailment="NONENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    My opponent stated thatquot;First and foremost, my opponent has dropped the issue of the Inconvenient truth documentaryquot; However, my entire case has been in contradiction to the inconvenient truth documentary, as seen when my opponent states quot;scientific evidence clearly backs up this claim in the documentary an inconvenient truthquot;, I have offered scientific in direct contradiction to the scientific evidence in the movie, thus I have negated my opponentapos;s ENTIRE argument. quot; As for the Popeapos;s contribution, this shows just how much climate change deniers are within the minority.quot;Seeing as my opponent likes to spew out the term quot;fallacyquot;, I will spew out the term band wagon fallacy which this argument is, because The bandwagon fallacy is committed by arguments that appeal to the growing popularity of an idea as a reason for accepting it as true. My opponent has admitted to doing this by sating that quot;climate change deniers are within the minorityquot; In my opponentapos;s (rather short) rebuttal he said that I was cherry picking again (in my first argument) He did show that I chose a time fame that best suits me, but that time frame that best suits me shows a DIRECT INDEPENDENCE between oil consumption and CO2 in the atmosphere. My opponent doesnapos;t seem to understand my argument that ATMOSPHERIC CO2 has no direct relationship to fossil fuel consumption, he lists the obvious fact that CO2 is released by the burning of fossil fuels, but shows no explanation to why an entire decade (and more) of data shows no relation between fossil fuel consumption and atmospheric CO2, in fact he drops the point in his second argument when he says he cannot explain why this statistic occurred. El nino was particularly potent in the spike of the graph.quot;I havenapos;t forgotten any claims that I have made, however my opponent has not shown anything contrary to my original claim, his only counter argument negates his entire argument when my opponent blames the spike in temperature on El Nino, a climate feature unrelated to Global Warming.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
  <pair id="50" entailment="ENTAILMENT" task="IE">
<t>    Fossil Fuels do not cause an increase in CO2 emissions, which makes the first part of the IPCCapos;s basic version of global warming invalidThis is overtly false, since science has shown repeatably that CO2 emissions increase green house gases. This is also stage 3c of climate change denial. [3]quot;The main human activity that emits CO2 is the combustion of fossil fuels (coal, natural gas, and oil) for energy and transportationquot; [2]From the above statement you can clearly see that burning oil causes green house gases. [3][4]s://grist.files.wordpress.com...; alt=quot;https://grist.files.wordpress.com...; /gt;Argument 3 Antarctic Ice was larger than ever in 2012 and 2014, thus the Antarctic Ice caps have not been melting which is thought to be a sideffect of the Global Warming theoryAntarctica ice is 1b stage of climate change denial. [5]4: There is no direct link between CO2 Emissions and Temperature IncreasesThis is stage 3c of climate change denial.</t>
    <h>Manmade global climate change is real and a threat.</h>
  </pair>
</entailment-corpus>
